<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin . is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-10-23T08:45:33Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Techno-Optimist Manifesto</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/techno-optimist-manifesto/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-23T08:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/techno-optimist-manifesto/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Marc Andreessen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/the-techno-optimist-manifesto/&quot;&gt;The Techno-Optimist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: compare to Communist Manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole intro is a lie. We are not being told any of these things. We are told to be weary of thechnology, to treat it with respect. With great power comes great responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, except I didn&#39;t realise the technology flag had been lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...  I agree with a lot of this. But he misses some major points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a problem of poverty, so we invent technology to create abundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abundance for some, but at the moment this abundance is being wasted by the few rather than put to good use for the many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe this is why our descendents will live in the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, can we live in the stars before we use up all the resources on the planet. We haven&#39;t yet turned the corner on wasting resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Markets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markets prevent monopolies and cartels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No they dont&#39;t. Plenty of monopolies in the world, also in the free capitalist world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe markets are an inherently individualistic way to achieve superior collective outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can believe that. Some people believe the earth is flat. It doesn&#39;t make it true. Where&#39;s the evidence for such a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe the ultimate moral defense of markets is that they divert people who otherwise would raise armies and start religions into peacefully productive pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if the spoils of the markets are fairly distributed. Not the case at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe markets are the way to generate societal wealth for everything else we want to pay for, including basic research, social welfare programs, and national defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we need social welfare programs if the markets actually worked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we need national defense, if we wereliving in the stars?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe a Universal Basic Income would turn people into zoo animals to be farmed by the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This I kind of agree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man was not meant to be farmed; man was meant to be useful, to be productive, to be proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, useful to whom? Productive for what? We were not &lt;strong&gt;meant&lt;/strong&gt; to be anything, we simply &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being proud probably helps though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of valid points in this section. But since he is saying markets support the welfare state, then they must be taxed and regulated, otherwise how will this support work. Not quite the free markets he is intending. Or else we understand different things in &amp;quot;free markets&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Techno-Capital Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole section reads like a description of Iain M Banks&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/archive/tagged/iain-banks/&quot;&gt;Culture Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course that is science fiction and doesn&#39;t have to deal with the limited resources on planet earth. Nevermind the limits of physics and the physiology of our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t help feeling that &amp;quot;accelerationism&amp;quot; as he calls it, doesn&#39;t quite lead to what he thinks. Acceleration tends to stretch things. If you are not careful, the link between those at the front doing the pulling (the few super rich), and those at the back being pulled along (the poor), risks breaking. We could end up living in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elysium_(film)&quot;&gt;Elysium&lt;/a&gt; style &amp;quot;utopia&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligence is inate. But being smart needs high quality education. Limiting high quality education to the rich, as is increasingly happening now, means the compound effect of &amp;quot;intelligence * education&amp;quot; is being woefully exploited. Since intelligence is inate, it is equally spread through the population. But when only one segment of the population gets to use that intelligence, you are missing out on an awful lot of intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this chapter was like &amp;quot;what is this guy on&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as people form symbiotic relationships with machines into new cybernetic systems such as companies and networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course AI can and is beneficial, but only because it is powered by human intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Energy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fully agree with the point made on energy consumption this section. We&#39;re not going to develop as a civilisation by using less energy. He also makes the point that using 1000x more energy does not need to be bad for the environment. I agree with that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then he says the current solution is nuclear fission. Whilst I don&#39;t disagree, I do think we need to urgently look beyond that technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He raises the prospect of nuclear fusion. Hopefully he is right on this. It can&#39;t come soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe technology is the solution to environmental degradation and crisis. A technologically advanced society improves the natural environment, a technologically stagnant society ruins it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are other ways in which an advanced can ruin the environment which he does not address (eg plastic pollution or habitat destruction), when it comes to energy, this is very true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abundance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the post-scarcity society of Iain M Banks culture series, which I already mentioned previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this section makes sense, although I never like it when people are referred to as resources, even if they are &amp;quot;ultimate resources&amp;quot; in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure we could support 50 billion people on planet earth, but if the age of abundance leads to a lack of need for material goods, maybe it could. But we would still need to eat and drink! And I hope we would not end up, perhaps even voluntarily, as batteries powering the matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not Utopia, But Close Enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, although this section doesn&#39;t really say anything concrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Becoming Technological Supermen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing particularly outrageous here. All fairly obvious, but then couched in weird wording:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in the romance of technology, of industry. The eros of the train, the car, the electric light, the skyscraper. And the microchip, the neural network, the rocket, the split atom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in adventure. Undertaking the Hero’s Journey, rebelling against the status quo, mapping uncharted territory, conquering dragons, and bringing home the spoils for our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does he even realise that he is the status quo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in nature, but we also believe in overcoming nature. We are not primitives, cowering in fear of the lightning bolt. We are the apex predator; the lightning works for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in greatness. We admire the great technologists and industrialists who came before us, and we aspire to make them proud of us today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we believe in humanity – individually and collectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, but please: &amp;quot;apex predators&amp;quot;? If we&#39;re not careful we will saw off the branch we are sitting on as we climb up the tree of technological greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technological Values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in ambition, aggression, persistence, relentlessness – strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds more like greed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in merit and achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merit is great, it&#39;s unfortunate that we increasingly live in a world where merit doesn&#39;t really figure much. And no money does not equal merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in embracing variance, in increasing interestingness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it&#39;s unfortunate that our technological progress is making the whole world look identical. Identikit streets, shops and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And freedom of thought is great, but how come then people are obsessed with a few &amp;quot;great&amp;quot; educational institutions. Where&#39;s the variance in everyone thinking like a Havard student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in radical competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this even mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe extrinsic motivations – wealth, fame, revenge – are fine as far as they go. But we believe intrinsic motivations – the satisfaction of building something new, the camaraderie of being on a team, the achievement of becoming a better version of oneself – are more fulfilling and more lasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew, he&#39;s not a complete capitalist then. Easy for someone to say who lucked into their first billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe technology is universalist. Technology doesn’t care about your ethnicity, race, religion, national origin, gender, sexuality, political views, height, weight, hair or lack thereof. Technology is built by a virtual United Nations of talent from all over the world. Anyone with a positive attitude and a cheap laptop can contribute. Technology is the ultimate open society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, technology is inclusive, if used correctly. Of course AI giving the job to the white guy rather than the black one is not fair or inclusive. It is simply following what it is trained on, subjective and biased decisions overwhelmingly made by white folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, there are still many people without even a cheap laptop. Probably over half the worls&#39;s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in the Silicon Valley code of “pay it forward”, trust via aligned incentives, generosity of spirit to help one another learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the silicon valley I observe through the media. Maybe in reality it really is like this. But I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe America and her allies should be strong and not weak. We believe national strength of liberal democracies flows from economic strength (financial power), cultural strength (soft power), and military strength (hard power). Economic, cultural, and military strength flow from technological strength. A technologically strong America is a force for good in a dangerous world. Technologically strong liberal democracies safeguard liberty and peace. Technologically weak liberal democracies lose to their autocratic rivals, making everyone worse off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fair point, if you consider the competing civilisations on this planet. I would rather we end up living in a democracy rather than an autocracy or dictatorship. But autocrats are currently making great use of technology to win their battles. Let&#39;s hope they don&#39;t win the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in fulfilling our potential, becoming fully human&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we are not currently &amp;quot;fully human&amp;quot;? If anything technology will make us less &amp;quot;human&amp;quot; with implants, replaced joints and who knows what enhancements in the future. I refer back to the Culture series...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Meaning of Life&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>IndieWeb</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/indieweb/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-16T00:33:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/indieweb/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I implemented some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;IndieWeb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;building blocks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I added &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/IndieAuth&quot;&gt;IndieAuth&lt;/a&gt; with GitHub account, testing it against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indielogin.com/api&quot;&gt;IndieLogin&lt;/a&gt; service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I added the required meta tags for &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/Webmention&quot;&gt;webmentions&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmention.io/&quot;&gt;webmention.io&lt;/a&gt; service to receive webmentions and pingbacks. Not that anyone is ever reading my blog or that I process the mentions... Still the site is setup for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/microformats&quot;&gt;microformat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/h-card&quot;&gt;h-card&lt;/a&gt; to my homepage in order to have business card like functionality on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, to wrap it all up, I added myself to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/indiewebring&quot;&gt;IndieWebRing&lt;/a&gt;, taking the lead from &lt;a href=&quot;https://jasm1nii.xyz/&quot;&gt;jasmine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://vanderven.se/martijn/&quot;&gt;Martin van der van&lt;/a&gt; on how to setup my h-card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having got started with microformats for the h-card, I went and added the required properties for &lt;a href=&quot;http://microformats.org/wiki/h-entry#Core_Properties&quot;&gt;h-entry&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Riverside</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/riverside/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-15T23:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/riverside/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A nice rock concert at Rockhal on Sunday evening, watching Polish band &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.riversideband.pl/en/&quot;&gt;Riverside&lt;/a&gt;, supported by Dutch group &lt;a href=&quot;https://lesoirmusic.com/home/&quot;&gt;Lesoir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lesoir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The support act, Lesoir, were good, with some nice songs. I felt they struggled a little to connect with the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/riverside-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riverside&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riverside were fantastic and put on a great show for the audience. The lead vocalist had a dry sense of humour which added to the atmosphere. No they are not like Dream Theatre, or Anathema. 64 members of the audience were from Luxembourg, the rest from elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/riverside-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/riverside-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Sign Language Evolution</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/sign-language-evolution/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-06T09:12:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/sign-language-evolution/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting image showing how sign languages around the world are connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sign-language-evolution.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Fischbach Circular Walk 1</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fischbach-circular-walk-1/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-05T17:43:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fischbach-circular-walk-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a simple 8.7km &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitluxembourg.com/tour/circular-walk-fischbach-i&quot;&gt;circular walk through the woods around Fischbach&lt;/a&gt;. It was a perfect cool early autumn afternoon for a fast paced walk with Angie. The page said the route takes two hours 30 minutes, but it took me and Angie only one hour and 45 minutes, which is what I would have expected for an 8km walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few hundred meters of the walk were quite steep uphill. After that it was really easy with only slight inclines, almost all of it in the woods. The walk was rather unspectacular, but it did serve as a nice couple of hours in woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fischbach-circular-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Mud Bath</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/mud-bath/"/>
		<updated>2023-09-15T20:23:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/mud-bath/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Keeping clean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/mud-bath-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/mud-bath-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Madeira for a week</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/madeira/"/>
		<updated>2023-09-02T17:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/madeira/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We spent a week on Madeira in the last week in August before the school holidays finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The house&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We booked what looked like a large house with pool and sea view somewhat above our usual price range and I wasn&#39;t sure what to expect. Well, we had the rare experience of the accomodation being exactly as advertised! A lovely sea view over the Arco da Calheta. The pool was large enough to almost swim lengths and play improvised water polo. The accomodation included a jacuzzi and a sauna, neither of which ended up using since the pool was enough. Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When picking up the car at the airport, a 1.2 litre Citroen, the lady at the desk was trying to get me to upgrade to a more powerful car for 200 Euro. She justified this given that Madeira had plenty of steep hills and given that there would be four of us in the car 1.2 litres might not be enough. I figured this was just a scam and chose not to. Well, I hadn&#39;t expected the roads to be quite so steep, especially off the main ones. Lack of power meant going uphill was largely done in first gear, unable to change up into second. Should we come again, I will try a more powerful car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The roads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A word on the road network on Madeira. I was really positively surprised by how well maintained and thought through the road network was. As mentioned above the roads were very steep at times, but the system of main roads was very easy to understand and to use. Essentially there are two levels of roads. Older ones, at the sea level, sometimes in need of a little maintenance. Whislst usually connecting the village, the idea of these roads was not to travel from village to village, but to access the local area (assesso local as the road signed indicated). About 50 metres above these local access roads, was the main road network, connecting the whole island. So to get from one village to another one further along, it would be more efficient to drive up to this level, get on the main roads and drive through the network of tunnels to your destination. The number of tunnels was astounding. Essentially these main roads are a set of tunnels which you only leave in order to get to the next village. So between two tunnels there would be a roundabout in order to get out of the tunnel network. Very simple and straightforward once you got the hang of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition I was also happy to see the driving was generally calm, unrushed and safe. Around Funchal you sometimes encountered someone in rush, probably because here there were two lanes in each direction. Once you were out of the city though, the roads were one lane each way, and being in a rush was simply of no use. Everyone drove at a reasonable speed, keeping a safe distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The climate and nature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a week of perfect weather. Not too hot, a little cloudy at times, pleasant in the evenings. Perfect. Up in the hills it was often cloudy, but down by the sea it was sunny. Madeira is full of Banana plantations on the hillsides around the coast. Higher up it takes on a distinct tropical feel. The terraced fields made it look like my memories of Bali. And some of the flora and fauna gave it a distinct Hawaii look and feel. Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-4-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1: Funchal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first full day we headed off to Funchal, had a walk around the sea front area and then got on the cable car up the hill to the Monte Park area. Here we walked around a little and visited the &amp;quot;Nossa Senhora do Monte&amp;quot; church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then walked all the steep 4km back down to the sea front. Our muscles thanked us the next day. An interesting aspect of this was walking alongside the levadas as we went. The levadas are a network of canals brining water from all over the island to where it is needed.  Usually you follow these on the walks in the centre of the island. I wasn&#39;t expecting to walk next to them in Funchal. They do flow at quite a speed in the steep parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the walk down, we sat in a poncha bar for a well deserved drink, before heading home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-8.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-9.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-10.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-11.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-12.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2: Madalena do mar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the steep walk down the hill from Monte in Funchal, we needed a bit of a rest on the next day. So we spent the morning enjoying the house, pool and view, before heading off for lunch in the Madalena do Mar village. We had noticed the previous day, which was a Sunday, that this village had been closed off by the police due to festival taking place there. It seemed like the whole of Madeira was going as the roads for chock a block full in the other direction, including many many special service buses taking people to the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-13.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The village has a nice sea front with a peble beach. We sat down in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/7Km7gGcxE6P8jZB87&quot;&gt;Restaurante Cantinho da Madalena&lt;/a&gt; restaurant for a lovely sea food meal. After that we headed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europeanwaterfalls.com/waterfalls/cascata-dos-anjos/&quot;&gt;Cascata dos Anjos&lt;/a&gt; watefall, which you can drive through with your car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-14.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished off the day in the pool followed by a relaxing meal on the terrace watching the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-15.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-16.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3: Fanal and Porto Moniz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afer taking it easy the previous day, we got up a little earlier and headed up the hill to the Fanal forest. The drive up was steep. Very steep. If there hadn&#39;t been cars similar to mine driving up in front of me, I might well have just turned round and gone to the beach. So after 20km or so of being stuck in first gear, we reached the Fanal forest area, which was completely covered in clouds. So the walk to Fio that we wanted to do with breathtaking views of the other side of Madeira wasn&#39;t really worthwhile, as we couldn&#39;t see more than 50 metres or so ahead. Instead we walked around the Fanal forest area, headed to the Fanal lake and walked back through fields taking care not to annoy the cows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-17.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-18.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-19.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-20.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-21.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the walk around Fanal forest, we headed down the hill to the north side of the island to Porto Moniz. Here we enjoyed the views, then had a nice lunch before walking round the natural pools (we didn&#39;t bring our bathing suits...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-22.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-23.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-24.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-25.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-26.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we headed back to our house to enjoy another nice evening watching the sunset. The kids also discovered that the previous occupants of the house had left their Netflix account on the TV, so that sorted us out for the evening, once it was dark!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-27.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 4: Risco waterfall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit more relaxed, we had a later start and headed to the waterfall area to see the Risco waterfall, which is on the same path as the 25 waterfalls which are further along. We hiked down a steep road for about 40 minutes before reaching the cafe for a brief rest stop. After that we carried on and followed the path to the Risco waterfall, which was very impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-28.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-29.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-30.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-31.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-32.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-33.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back as we were discussing the merits of hiking back up the steep road or getting the bus, two buses turned up and made the decision for us. This shortened the day somewhat, but meant we had more time to relax back at the pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we then headed to the Calheta marina area for a lovely dinner and late evening walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-34.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 5: Hike at peninsula&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous evening we had stayed up trying to watch the blue supermoon, which apparently appear irregularly once every 10 years or so, the next one being in 2037.  It had still not appeared from behind the cliff by the time I went to bed. However it was still hangning around when I woke up around 7.30am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-35.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-36.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our last but one day we decided to do the &amp;quot;Sao Lorenco&amp;quot; hike. After a late start to the day, we headed off around 11am and arrived at midday. That was a mistake. Apparently we were not the only ones doing this hike, as we had to park about a 20 minute walk from the trail head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hike itself was great. Steep at times and quite busy on the narrower parts with no shade, at all. This meant we were sweltering in the sun all afternoon, except for at the cafe at the end of the trail. It was a lovely walk from which we arrived back home exhausted and hungry. So we headed for the &amp;quot;Manifattura Di Gelato&amp;quot; Italian restaurant at the marina we ate at the previous meaning. The food was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-37.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-38.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-39.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-40.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-41.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 6:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final day was calm affair. We woke up late and hung out at the pool for a while, cleaned the house a little in preparation for our depature the next morning at 4.30am. We then headed back to the restaurant in Madalena do mar which we enjoyed so much on the second day. After another great lunch, we went to Funchal for a little souvenir shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some final photos of the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-42.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-43.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/madeira-44.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Around Bofferdange</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/around-bofferange/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-24T07:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/around-bofferange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some photos from my local area in Bofferdange, Luxembourg. It&#39;s very pretty when it&#39;s sunny. Right now it&#39;s pouring down! 😒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow over a valley, in front and through the clouds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Green valley with wooded hills in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Wheat kernel in front of the morning sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Stacks of harvested wheat waiting in the field to be collected in the morning sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Hydrogen Sonata</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/hyrdogen-sonata/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-22T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/hyrdogen-sonata/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His final Culture Series novel before his death marks a very fitting end to the series. It covers the notion of Subliming, where by advanced galactic civilisations voluntarily dissapear into the &amp;quot;Ether&amp;quot; as they feel their time in the &amp;quot;Real&amp;quot; is finished. As such it has some qualities of death itself. I don&#39;t think Banks knew he had cancer when writing this book. Judging by the interview in the back of the book he was planning on writing more Culture novels. Sadly that will not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions this book asks is do you tell your good friend and distant relative that the whole basis and meaning of their life was a lie just before they die. You know they have this suspicion, but still they believe they lie. Do you tell them or do you let them go to the other side believing a lie? Perhaps it doesn&#39;t matter even if you tell them. They like the lie too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/hydrogen-sonata.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Manifesto of the Communist Party</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/communist-manifesto/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-21T07:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/communist-manifesto/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/communist-manifesto.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussing some of Iain M Banks&#39; socialist theories in his Culture novels, a friend of mine commented: &amp;quot;but that&#39;s from Karl Marx&#39;s Communist Manifesto&amp;quot;. I figured it might be good to read the manifesto, so I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1848/communist-manifesto/index.htm&quot;&gt;downloaded and printed it out from the internet&lt;/a&gt;. At around 50 pages it&#39;s quite short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my random thoughts on the manifesto. &lt;strong&gt;They are probably wrong&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I thought there were a lot valid points criticising capitalism in this chapter. However I can&#39;t help feeling that the end state of the Communist Manifesto is some sort Utopia in permanent stasis. But this is not realistic, change is the basis of life and trying to oppose the forces of change always fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked this paragraph as it still seems relevant today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is enough to mention the commercial crises that by their periodical return put the existence of the entire bourgeois society on its trial, each time more threateningly. In these crises, a great part not only of the existing products, but also of the previously created productive forces, are periodically destroyed. In these crises, there breaks out an epidemic that, in all earlier epochs, would have seemed an absurdity — the epidemic of over-production&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t like the idea of the proletariat overthrowing the bourgoisie being the legitimate end game and that only the proletariat class seem to have some god given right to survive. The proletatriat will need leaders, which will attract the power hungry and off we go again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as, therefore, at an earlier period, a section of the nobility went over to the bourgeoisie, so now a portion of the bourgeoisie goes over to the proletariat, and in particular, a portion of the bourgeois ideologists, who have raised themselves to the level of comprehending theoretically the historical movement as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the classes that stand face to face with the bourgeoisie today, the proletariat alone is a really revolutionary class. The other classes decay and finally disappear in the face of Modern Industry; the proletariat is its special and essential product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will just &amp;quot;rinse-repeat&amp;quot;. Round and round we go. Why should the proletariat be different to the peasants in previous centuries? The premise appears to be that technological progress is the difference between now and then. But I don&#39;t buy that. Unless of course thechnology is used to maintain the whole thing by force, as happened in eastern Europe - poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Communists, therefore, are on the one hand, practically, the most advanced and resolute section of the working-class parties of every country, that section which pushes forward all others; on the other hand, theoretically, they have over the great mass of the proletariat the advantage of clearly understanding the line of march, the conditions, and the ultimate general results of the proletarian movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the &amp;quot;Communists&amp;quot; will be the better amongst equals, because what, they are better educated? But they are better educated because they come from the upper classes. As invariably always happens, the Communists will end up ruling over the proletariat, not with them...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, there are some very good and valid criticism of capitalism, but only poor solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National differences and antagonism between peoples are daily more and more vanishing, owing to the development of the bourgeoisie, to freedom of commerce, to the world market, to uniformity in the mode of production and in the conditions of life corresponding thereto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supremacy of the proletariat will cause them to vanish still faster. United action, of the leading civilised countries at least, is one of the first conditions for the emancipation of the proletariat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In proportion as the exploitation of one individual by another will also be put an end to, the exploitation of one nation by another will also be put an end to. In proportion as the antagonism between classes within the nation vanishes, the hostility of one nation to another will come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As above, how can action only involving leading civilised countries, be considered &amp;quot;united action&amp;quot;? Who&#39;s defining &amp;quot;civilised&amp;quot; here? No mention in this book of Africa for example. Don&#39;t they get a say? Again, better among equals...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the proletariat during its contest with the bourgeoisie is compelled, by the force of circumstances, to organise itself as a class, if, by means of a revolution, it makes itself the ruling class, and, as such, sweeps away by force the old conditions of production, then it will, along with these conditions, have swept away the conditions for the existence of class antagonisms and of classes generally, and will thereby have abolished its own supremacy as a class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the utopia of communism. It is also wishful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tour de table of different types of communism that have or would fail, followed by the assumption that Marx&#39;s &amp;quot;communism&amp;quot; will not. Feudal Socialism, Petty Bourgoise Socialism, German or True Socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the latter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve this class is to preserve the existing state of things in Germany. The industrial and political supremacy of the bourgeoisie threatens it with certain destruction — on the one hand, from the concentration of capital; on the other, from the rise of a revolutionary proletariat. “True” Socialism appeared to kill these two birds with one stone. It spread like an epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Conservative or Bourgoise Socialism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A part of the bourgeoisie is desirous of redressing social grievances in order to secure the continued existence of bourgeois society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this section belong economists, philanthropists, humanitarians, improvers of the condition of the working class, organisers of charity, members of societies for the prevention of cruelty to animals, temperance fanatics, hole-and-corner reformers of every imaginable kind. This form of socialism has, moreover, been worked out into complete systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this description - very good! Fully agree, this is some sort of half way house to keep the rich in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They wish for a bourgeoisie without a proletariat. The bourgeoisie naturally conceives the world in which it is supreme to be the best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second, and more practical, but less systematic, form of this Socialism sought to depreciate every revolutionary movement in the eyes of the working class by showing that no mere political reform, but only a change in the material conditions of existence, in economical relations, could be of any advantage to them.....but administrative reforms, based on the continued existence of these relations; reforms, therefore, that in no respect affect the relations between capital and labour, but, at the best, lessen the cost, and simplify the administrative work, of bourgeois government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bourgeois Socialism attains adequate expression when, and only when, it becomes a mere figure of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free trade: for the benefit of the working class. Protective duties: for the benefit of the working class. Prison Reform: for the benefit of the working class. This is the last word and the only seriously meant word of bourgeois socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is summed up in the phrase: the bourgeois is a bourgeois — for the benefit of the working class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we seem to be in this form of socialism. The question is: where will it end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter considers that Germany, at the time, was closest to some half way house to Communism and therefore had quite a small proletariat. They were still fighting the aristocracy. Interesting that less than 100 years later the Nazis were in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in the appenices to the docmument, Engels, in &amp;quot;Principles of Communism&amp;quot;, considers the revolution will be easiest in England, hardest in Germany, based on the relvative sizes of the proletariat in those countries - larger in England, smaller in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the manifesto is very open about the probable need for forced / armed revolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all these movements, they bring to the front, as the leading question in each, the property question, no matter what its degree of development at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Communists disdain to conceal their views and aims. They openly declare that their ends can be attained only by the forcible overthrow of all existing social conditions. Let the ruling classes tremble at a Communistic revolution. The proletarians have nothing to lose but their chains. They have a world to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you have to fight for what you believe is right. Forcing others against their will to believe it will never work. There will always be those who don&#39;t believe. Suppressing them doesn&#39;t work for long.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
