<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>robin.is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-05-02T07:23:28Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>John Greenwood</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/john-greenwood/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-02T07:23:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/john-greenwood/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Racing&#39;s in the family. John Greenwood is a relative of the family on my mother&#39;s side. He was a successfull Speedway racer until a racing accident left him with one arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/john-greenwood.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Eight Monarchs team speedway racers posing for a team photo with three in the front and five at the back. Back row: Roy Bester, Eddie Lack, Johnny Greenwood, Dick Campbell, Bert Clark. Kneeling on the front row: Don Cuppleditch, Bob Mark, Jimmy Cox.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image and text taken from an article by John Hyam on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.speedwaymuseumonline.co.uk/johngreenwood.html&quot;&gt;Speedway Museum Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the article so I have a local copy in case that link breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONE of speedway&#39;s tragedies is when a potentially brilliant career is shattered by injury. There have been many instances over the years, and one that especially stands out in my mind concerns Johnny Greenwood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was just 21 years old when his career came to a shuddering end in 1956 more than 6,000 miles away from his home at Keighley in Yorkshire. It happened at Adelaide when he broke his right arm which was left partially paralysed bringing an abrupt end to a promising career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Walsh, a former cycle speedway rider from Keighley in Yorkshire, has been a lifelong friend of Greenwood. Bill said, &amp;quot;I first met Johnny when we were pupils at Keighley Boys Grammar School and we are still in regular contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He was taken to ride in Australia by Fred Tracey, the old Walthamstow and Coventry rider, who was then the Melbourne promoter. He did so well at Melbourne that it was decided to take Johnny on to race at Adelaide where Jack Young was the big star. And Johnny&#39;s winning ways meant that he was soon a backmarker off 200 yards in handicap races. Only Young was given a bigger handicap - 20 yards behind Greenwood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On the night of his accident, Johnny was going for an unbeaten run. In his last race of the meeting he passed Bob &#39;Cowboy&#39; Sharp on the third lap to go in front. Then, for some unexplained reason, Johnny seemed to lose concentration and slammed into the safety fence on the third bend of the last lap.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walsh added, &amp;quot;He was badly injured and severely damaged the nerves in his arm which eventually led to the permanent loss of it. At 21 it was as bad as it could get.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a 17-year-old. Greenwood had been a protege of Ernie Appleby at his Newton Heath training track near Manchester in 1953. Before the year was out Johnny had rides with Liverpool in National League Division Two, then finished the season at Southern League track St Austell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of 1954, Greenwood was with Edinburgh in their brief early season in the National League Division Two where he averaged 8.29 points in four league matches. His debut meeting at Meadowbank was in a pairs event where he took 13 points in his five rides and only renowned Scottish stars Ken McKinlay and Don Cuppleditch beat him. It made Greenwood an overnight favourite with Monarchs&#39; fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of Greenwood&#39;s brief spell at Edinburgh was his fiery style of riding when partnered with Don Cuppleditch.  When Cuppleditch led in races, Greenwood was always hot on his tail, but when the placings were reversed there was no way the heat leader could get back in front. And when Edinburgh faced Leicester in the National Trophy, Greenwood returned paid double figure scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of Greenwood&#39;s attitude to racing was that he hated to be passed when in front. McKinlay once said, &amp;quot;After a race in which he had been overtaken, Johnny asked me to explain just how his rival had managed to get past him. He was a true racer and dedicated to winning.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closure of Edinburgh early in the season saw Greenwood move to Exeter, before the calls of National Service took him to Iraq for two years. Upon demob and with the 1956 season coming to an end, Greenwood joined Division One side Bradford, making just two appearances. And it was while racing at Bradford that Aussie track boss Fred Tracey was captivated by the youngster&#39;s spectacular style and invited him to go to Australia - a venture that was to end his racing career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious injury did not see an end to Greenwood&#39;s love of life generally nor of speedway. He married and raised two sons and still takes a keen interest in speedway at Grand Prix level, and especially likes to see the meetings in Poland. Additionally, he is an enthusiastic member of the World Speedway Riders Association.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Grünewald Circular Walk</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/grunewald-circular-walk/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-01T20:23:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/grunewald-circular-walk/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a simple 4.5km &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitluxembourg.com/tour/circular-walk-grengewald&quot;&gt;circular walk around the Grünewald woods above Walferdange&lt;/a&gt;. It was a reasonably warm Labour day for a slow stroll around the local woods. It took about an hour and a quarter with grand parents and Angie. Very simple with one slightly steep short uphill part which was a challenge for the older folk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/grunewald-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/grunewald-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Wavewalker</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wavewalker/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-30T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wavewalker/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Suzanne Heywood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book depicts the 10 years the author spent sailing around the world with her parents and younger brother. She departed England at the age of seven on their boat, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.bookshop.org/p/books/wavewalker-suzanne-heywood/6898356?ean=9780008498498&quot;&gt;Wavewalker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s quite an adventure, including a near death experience in the Indian Ocean a couple of years into the trip. However the actual story of the book is that of a young girl spending the best 10 years of her youth lonely at sea, rather than socialising with friends at school.  Whilst the story turns out well, with the author going to Oxford University, the author is clear: this was not the idylic childhood her parents pretended she had and she has the psychological scars to show it. The fact that she coped so well is quite a miracle. She was more often than not neglected by her parents, both psychologically and physically. They essentially abandoned her in the middle of nowhere in New Zealand to look after her brother, whilst the parents continued sailing to &amp;quot;earn money&amp;quot;. She finally &amp;quot;escaped&amp;quot; to England for an interview at Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An easy read and well told story. I finished it whilst &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/&quot;&gt;travelling to Malta&lt;/a&gt; and back. A little repetitive at times, but then I guess that is the point. The 10 years were not all fun and games. At all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/wavewalker.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>INHOPE in Malta</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-28T07:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last couple of days I was in Malta in order to give a presentation to &lt;a href=&quot;https://inhope.org/EN&quot;&gt;INHOPE&lt;/a&gt; on how to ensure their hotlines are accessible. I got there via a change in Frankfurt and returned the same way. The one thing I love about flying between Schengen countries is that there are no border controls. This meant that the only point I had to show my ID card during the whole trip was first in Luxembourg to check I am the person it says on my ticket when entering the security checks and then when checking in at the hotel. Fantastic! It makes getting out of airports so much easier, especially if you only have hand luggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-landing.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Landing in Malta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a 25 minute taxi ride to the hotel I checked in and then explored the area a little. Getting to the conference venue would be a pleasant 15 minute stroll in the morning. The immediate area around my hotel, whilst OK, wasn&#39;t anything worth writing home about from a tourist point of view. But then this was a work trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-st-julian.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Small maltese cove in the sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference, which was actually an INHOPE Hotline Training Meeting took place in the Grand Ballroom of the Raddisson Blu.  I wasn&#39;t expecting this. Rarely giving presentations and if so maybe in front of 10 people or online, when I accepted to give the presentation I was expecting something quite small. When I was told it would be about 60 people, I asumed this was an exaggeration. It turned out to possibly be an underestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-grand-ballroom.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Ballroom with three chandeliers with the screen at the back showing the slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is a photo of me in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-me.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Me, microphone in one hand, speaking next to the podium looking back at the big screen displaying types of disabilities. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after the arrival I followed the conference with interest. In the evening I walked around a bit more, this time in the other direction (a little to the south-east), passed Spinola Bay and around St. Julian&#39;s Bay. I found that direction to be a little more interesting with a nicer beach walk. I caught a glimpse of the Balluta Building and the church next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-view-balluta.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Impressive art nouveau Balluta Building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I returned to the hotel to prepare for my presentation the next morning. This went much better than I was expecting with a number of hotline representatives asking me to send them my presentation. After lunch, I went to the airport to catch my flight back. So I didn&#39;t get to see a lot of Malta. I enjoyed the sun and warmth and the somewhat arabic architecture of the buildings. The conference was insightful and my presentation a success. So overall a good two days away and on the flight back I got a nice view of the alps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-alps.webp&quot; alt=&quot;View of the snow capped Alps through the airplane window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Stroll in the Steinsel woods</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/roman-steinsel/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-23T19:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/roman-steinsel/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A nice little walk in the woods above Steinsel with Angie. I came across &amp;quot;Yet Another Roman Ruin&amp;quot;. Discovered in 1957 apparently. Not sure the columns are actually real. Good for effect though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/roman-steinsel.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Ruins of a Roman site in a wooded area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Goodbye to Wordpress</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wordpress/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-13T09:33:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wordpress/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I deleted my remaining Wordpress sites and cancelled my Wordpress account. And so ends over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/history/&quot;&gt;13 years of Wordpress hosting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since moving my site to Eleventy, I had kept my two remaining Wordpress sites online only because an old post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2013/epson-scan-window-wont-open/&quot;&gt;Epson printer window&lt;/a&gt; on one site was still quite popular. But that post no longer got any hits in the last couple of years, so it was OK to turn off the site. That left one remaining site where I had a collected a few paintings of mine. I copied those to this site as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/&quot;&gt;post called Creative Eye&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always liked &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, the internet&#39;s most successful CMS platform. It&#39;s open source nature and the philosophy of it&#39;s creator certainly appealed to me. It was easy to install when self-hosting and easy to use whether self-hosted or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;. And the price point was perfect: $0. Something I blogged about a while back when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2021/netlify-wordpress/&quot;&gt;comparing it to JAMStack sites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in recent years I did find the act of writing a post got more complex than it needed to be. The Guttenberg editor was surely a reason for this. I never quite got the hang of it, even if I could understand the idea behind it. On top of this, the sheer number of options meant it was sometimes hard to find where to do what if you didn&#39;t use the tool regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I say goodbye to Wordpress not because it is a bad choice of CMS, but because I found a setup more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/replacing-forestry/&quot;&gt;suitable for my needs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Creative Eye</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-12T19:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are 12 images copied from an old and now defunct websites of mine: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cr8iveye.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Cr8ive Eye&lt;/a&gt;. Of course that link now no longer works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subtitle of the site: The creative failures of an artistic illeterate! [sic]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-lines.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Lines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Dots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-dots.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Dots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Crosses and Squiggles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/squiggles.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Crosses and Squiggles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/shinkansen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rural Road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rural-road.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rural Road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sunset.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creative Eye&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/creative-eye.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Creative Eye&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blue Vase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/blue-vase.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Vase&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Snake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/snake.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Snake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Three Seasons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/three-seasons.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Three Seasons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angry-birds.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angry Birds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jungle Picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/jungle-picture.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Jungle Picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Easter Weekend in Istanbul</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/easter-in-istanbul/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-11T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/easter-in-istanbul/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in March &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flypgs.com/en&quot;&gt;Pegasus airlines&lt;/a&gt; opened a new route from Plovdiv to Istanbul, so we thought we would give it a go when we went to Plovdiv for the Easter holidays. I booked some tickets €70 return per person which seemed a reasonable price. I also booked the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tr/sapphire.html&quot;&gt;Sapphire Hotel&lt;/a&gt; for three nights in the Fatih area of Istanbul, right next door to the Topkapi Palace, Ayasofya Mosque and the Sultanahmet Mosque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our flight landed on time in Sabiha Gökcen airport and we proceeded to the exit of gate 13 where the hotel said we will find our pre-booked transfer. What a welcome to Turkey that was! We found the right location, but there were many others looking for a transfer at the same location and we were approached by several drivers offering a transfer, none of whom seemed to know our name or our destination. Not having roaming, I was unable to contact the hotel. After some standing around, looking like useless tourists (which we were), we eventually managed to get a transfer for €45, which was €5 less than the hotel had stated us. And so began our adrenalin fueled taxi ride from another dimension...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got in the cab and set off, a short while later the cab driver pulled into a nearby petrol station to refuel. Not for petrol as you might expect, but for RedBull and cigarettes. And so the fun began. More thrilling than a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vdl.lu/fr/node/11240&quot;&gt;Schueberfouer&lt;/a&gt; ride, more dangerous than a shuttle launch and more scary than a Stephen King movie: our taxi driver was weaving in and out of traffic on the motorway into town, whilst holding a can of RedBull in one hand, a cigarette in the other, speaking to god knows who on one phone and using Google translate to give me the tourist highlights on another all whilst changing gears with the wrong hand. After too many &amp;quot;beyond close&amp;quot; calls with other cars on the road, including several where I thought &amp;quot;that was a nice life, unfortunatrly didn&#39;t quite make it to 50&amp;quot;, we promptly hit peak traffic around our hotel and didn&#39;t move for a good 20 minutes whilst we were a 15 minutes walk from our hotel! After several more twists and turns to get passed multiple cars on streets too narrow for even one car, the driver stopped, pulled in between two traffic cones and said: &amp;quot;this as close as I can get you, your hotel is down that road first on your left&amp;quot;. So we got out, I gave a €5 tip and we got to our hotel a few minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - Easter Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started off on this cold, but sunny day, by walking around Gülhane park which is next to Topkapi palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/gulhane-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Gülhane Sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tulips had been planted in the park for Istanbul&#39;s Tulip festival which is in the whole month of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/gulhane-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Gulhane Tulips&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the northern end of the park we had a look at the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/bosphorus.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Bosphorus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed back to the entrance of the Topkapi palace. Unfortunately the queues were so long we headed on to the Ayasofya Mosque only to be confronted by even longer queues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ayasofya.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Ayasofya Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be dispirited, we continued on to the Sultanahmet Mosque only to see that it was temporarily closed for restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sultanahmet.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sultanahment Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would explain why the other two queues were so long. That and the fact the place was full of Easter weekend tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed onto the Mosaic Museum, via a nice market, but that was also shut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/spice-stall.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Market stall selling spice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now it was time for lunch, which we had on a roof top terrace that afforded great views of both the Bosphorus and the Sultanahmet Mosque. The food was also very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sultanahmet-rooftop.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sultanahmet from roof top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having relaxed a bit on the terrace we headed to the spice market on the other side of the Fatih quarter. Whilst interesting, spice wasn&#39;t the only thing they sold here, which made it feel like just another market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/spice-market.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Spice market&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having failed to get into any of the mosques in the Topkapi palace area, we were happy to have a look inside the Yeni Mosque, just next to the spice market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/yeni-mosque.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yeni Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we could also see the Galata tower and were discussing on the merits of getting the tram across the bridge or walking when a guy managed to convince us to get on a one hour cruise around the Bosphorus. He gave us about 50% off the regular price, which we later realised was because it was probably the last cruise of the day and the boat was quite empty. Still, this meant we got good views as we sailed up and down a section of the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the riverside views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/galata-tower.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Galata Tower&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/yeni-rustem-mosques.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yeni and Rüstem Pasha mosques&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/asian-side-flag-tower.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Asian side with the largest mosque, flag and tower&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/flags.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Flags&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 - Easter Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second day in Istanbul was essentially a day of cold and rain. The good thing about this was that it forced us to figure out the public transport and the benefits of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://istanbulepass.com/how-to-get-istanbul-kart.html&quot;&gt;Istanbul Card&lt;/a&gt;. The card costs 50TL and using it you get roughly half price fares compared to the regular fare. The best part being that you can share the card between five people, so no need to spend 200TL for the family just on cards. By sharing the card between the four of us, we recuperated the cost of the card after a couple of journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we headed to Taksim square first on the tram and then up the hill with the funicular (which is a regular part of the public transport system and not a tourist thing). As it hadn&#39;t stopped raining, we stopped off in a nearby cafe for an hour or so and had a nice Turkish coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/taksim-square.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Taksim Square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it had more or less stopped raining we carried on walking through Taskim park, passed the technical university and down the hill along the Beshiktas football stadium and back to where we got off the tram. Since we hadn&#39;t yet been to the asian part (except for our mad taxi drive at the beginning) we got the ferry to the other side of the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beshiktas-stadium.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Beshiktas Stadium&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the asian side we walked north-east along the riverside in the Üsküdar district. Then we walked up the hill through a little park and back down to the ferry station along the main road. This gave us a better feel for what might be the more normal Istanbul away from the maddening tourist crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/uskundar-park.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Üsküdar park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned back to the Fatih district on the Marmaray train. This was an efficient, if dull, experience. It got us back to Fatih in about 3 minutes! Having spent the day getting around on various forms of public transport (tram, funicular, boat and train) I have to say that I am impressed with the public transport in this city. Still the roads are blocked full of cars! Maybe the day to day experience of public transport is different to the tourist one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the day with a lovely meal in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/saluteistanbul/&quot;&gt;Salute Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;, 100 metres from our hotel. Definitely recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fruit-salad.webp&quot;&gt;Desert fruit salad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 - Return home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our flight home was in the late afternoon and checkout was at midday, so we walked around the Topkapi area in the hope of there being no queues after the easter weekend. We were mistaken, but did manage to get into the Sultan Ahmed Tomb which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/tomb.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Tomb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we headed back to the hotel, grabbed our bags and got in the pre-booked taxi back to the airport. This time it was a normal drive along the motorway. No thrills, no danger, no scares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/bridge-taxi.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge from Taxi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-09T09:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th April is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today my site is naked.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Folkdance Ensemble Trakia</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-07T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely evening, this time watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trakia-ensemble.org/en/&quot;&gt;folkdance ensemble Trakia&lt;/a&gt; perform at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://domborishristov.com/&quot;&gt;House of culture in Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
