<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>robin.is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-05-18T19:18:27Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Restaurant Computer Systems</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/rcs/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-18T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/rcs/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spotted this display of Luxembourg&#39;s Restaurant Computer Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in 1982 and 1984 with a Commodore computer, moving to an Amiga and Kaypro in 1986, then to a touchscreen in 2003 and finally a tablet in 2023. Which one do you think is most usable? Personally I would go for the 2003 touchscreen, but I can understand the convenience of a tablet which the staff can carry around. But is that really an improvement on a pen and paper? 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rcs-84-commodore.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Commodore computer from 1984&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rcs-86-amiga.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Amiga computer from 1986&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rcs-86-kaypro.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Kaypro computer from 1986&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rcs-03-23.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Touchscreen computer from 2003 next to a tablet from 2023&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dog on a log - four seasons</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-four-seasons/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-05T09:30:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-four-seasons/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Angie on a log across the four seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angie-four-seaons.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Dog sitting on a log in Spring, Summer, Autumn and Winter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-spring/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Spring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/dog-on-a-log-again/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Summer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2021/dog-log/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Autumn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-yet-again/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Winter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dog on a log - in spring</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-spring/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-04T20:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-spring/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The final photo in the four seasons series of Angie sitting on a log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/dog-on-a-log-spring.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Dog sitting on a log in the spring forst&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-yet-again/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Winter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2021/dog-log/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Autumn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/dog-on-a-log-again/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Summer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>John Greenwood</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/john-greenwood/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-02T07:23:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/john-greenwood/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Racing&#39;s in the family. John Greenwood is a relative of the family on my mother&#39;s side. He was a successfull Speedway racer until a racing accident left him with one arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/john-greenwood.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Eight Monarchs team speedway racers posing for a team photo with three in the front and five at the back. Back row: Roy Bester, Eddie Lack, Johnny Greenwood, Dick Campbell, Bert Clark. Kneeling on the front row: Don Cuppleditch, Bob Mark, Jimmy Cox.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image and text taken from an article by John Hyam on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.speedwaymuseumonline.co.uk/johngreenwood.html&quot;&gt;Speedway Museum Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the article so I have a local copy in case that link breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONE of speedway&#39;s tragedies is when a potentially brilliant career is shattered by injury. There have been many instances over the years, and one that especially stands out in my mind concerns Johnny Greenwood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was just 21 years old when his career came to a shuddering end in 1956 more than 6,000 miles away from his home at Keighley in Yorkshire. It happened at Adelaide when he broke his right arm which was left partially paralysed bringing an abrupt end to a promising career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Walsh, a former cycle speedway rider from Keighley in Yorkshire, has been a lifelong friend of Greenwood. Bill said, &amp;quot;I first met Johnny when we were pupils at Keighley Boys Grammar School and we are still in regular contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He was taken to ride in Australia by Fred Tracey, the old Walthamstow and Coventry rider, who was then the Melbourne promoter. He did so well at Melbourne that it was decided to take Johnny on to race at Adelaide where Jack Young was the big star. And Johnny&#39;s winning ways meant that he was soon a backmarker off 200 yards in handicap races. Only Young was given a bigger handicap - 20 yards behind Greenwood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On the night of his accident, Johnny was going for an unbeaten run. In his last race of the meeting he passed Bob &#39;Cowboy&#39; Sharp on the third lap to go in front. Then, for some unexplained reason, Johnny seemed to lose concentration and slammed into the safety fence on the third bend of the last lap.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walsh added, &amp;quot;He was badly injured and severely damaged the nerves in his arm which eventually led to the permanent loss of it. At 21 it was as bad as it could get.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a 17-year-old. Greenwood had been a protege of Ernie Appleby at his Newton Heath training track near Manchester in 1953. Before the year was out Johnny had rides with Liverpool in National League Division Two, then finished the season at Southern League track St Austell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of 1954, Greenwood was with Edinburgh in their brief early season in the National League Division Two where he averaged 8.29 points in four league matches. His debut meeting at Meadowbank was in a pairs event where he took 13 points in his five rides and only renowned Scottish stars Ken McKinlay and Don Cuppleditch beat him. It made Greenwood an overnight favourite with Monarchs&#39; fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of Greenwood&#39;s brief spell at Edinburgh was his fiery style of riding when partnered with Don Cuppleditch.  When Cuppleditch led in races, Greenwood was always hot on his tail, but when the placings were reversed there was no way the heat leader could get back in front. And when Edinburgh faced Leicester in the National Trophy, Greenwood returned paid double figure scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A feature of Greenwood&#39;s attitude to racing was that he hated to be passed when in front. McKinlay once said, &amp;quot;After a race in which he had been overtaken, Johnny asked me to explain just how his rival had managed to get past him. He was a true racer and dedicated to winning.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closure of Edinburgh early in the season saw Greenwood move to Exeter, before the calls of National Service took him to Iraq for two years. Upon demob and with the 1956 season coming to an end, Greenwood joined Division One side Bradford, making just two appearances. And it was while racing at Bradford that Aussie track boss Fred Tracey was captivated by the youngster&#39;s spectacular style and invited him to go to Australia - a venture that was to end his racing career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious injury did not see an end to Greenwood&#39;s love of life generally nor of speedway. He married and raised two sons and still takes a keen interest in speedway at Grand Prix level, and especially likes to see the meetings in Poland. Additionally, he is an enthusiastic member of the World Speedway Riders Association.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Grünewald Circular Walk</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/grunewald-circular-walk/"/>
		<updated>2023-05-01T20:23:28Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/grunewald-circular-walk/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a simple 4.5km &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitluxembourg.com/tour/circular-walk-grengewald&quot;&gt;circular walk around the Grünewald woods above Walferdange&lt;/a&gt;. It was a reasonably warm Labour day for a slow stroll around the local woods. It took about an hour and a quarter with grand parents and Angie. Very simple with one slightly steep short uphill part which was a challenge for the older folk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/grunewald-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/grunewald-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Wavewalker</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wavewalker/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-30T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wavewalker/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Suzanne Heywood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book depicts the 10 years the author spent sailing around the world with her parents and younger brother. She departed England at the age of seven on their boat, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.bookshop.org/p/books/wavewalker-suzanne-heywood/6898356?ean=9780008498498&quot;&gt;Wavewalker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s quite an adventure, including a near death experience in the Indian Ocean a couple of years into the trip. However the actual story of the book is that of a young girl spending the best 10 years of her youth lonely at sea, rather than socialising with friends at school.  Whilst the story turns out well, with the author going to Oxford University, the author is clear: this was not the idylic childhood her parents pretended she had and she has the psychological scars to show it. The fact that she coped so well is quite a miracle. She was more often than not neglected by her parents, both psychologically and physically. They essentially abandoned her in the middle of nowhere in New Zealand to look after her brother, whilst the parents continued sailing to &amp;quot;earn money&amp;quot;. She finally &amp;quot;escaped&amp;quot; to England for an interview at Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An easy read and well told story. I finished it whilst &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/&quot;&gt;travelling to Malta&lt;/a&gt; and back. A little repetitive at times, but then I guess that is the point. The 10 years were not all fun and games. At all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/wavewalker.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>INHOPE in Malta</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-28T07:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inhope-malta/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the last couple of days I was in Malta in order to give a presentation to &lt;a href=&quot;https://inhope.org/EN&quot;&gt;INHOPE&lt;/a&gt; on how to ensure their hotlines are accessible. I got there via a change in Frankfurt and returned the same way. The one thing I love about flying between Schengen countries is that there are no border controls. This meant that the only point I had to show my ID card during the whole trip was first in Luxembourg to check I am the person it says on my ticket when entering the security checks and then when checking in at the hotel. Fantastic! It makes getting out of airports so much easier, especially if you only have hand luggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-landing.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Landing in Malta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a 25 minute taxi ride to the hotel I checked in and then explored the area a little. Getting to the conference venue would be a pleasant 15 minute stroll in the morning. The immediate area around my hotel, whilst OK, wasn&#39;t anything worth writing home about from a tourist point of view. But then this was a work trip!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-st-julian.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Small maltese cove in the sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference, which was actually an INHOPE Hotline Training Meeting took place in the Grand Ballroom of the Raddisson Blu.  I wasn&#39;t expecting this. Rarely giving presentations and if so maybe in front of 10 people or online, when I accepted to give the presentation I was expecting something quite small. When I was told it would be about 60 people, I asumed this was an exaggeration. It turned out to possibly be an underestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-grand-ballroom.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Ballroom with three chandeliers with the screen at the back showing the slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is a photo of me in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-me.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Me, microphone in one hand, speaking next to the podium looking back at the big screen displaying types of disabilities. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after the arrival I followed the conference with interest. In the evening I walked around a bit more, this time in the other direction (a little to the south-east), passed Spinola Bay and around St. Julian&#39;s Bay. I found that direction to be a little more interesting with a nicer beach walk. I caught a glimpse of the Balluta Building and the church next to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-view-balluta.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Impressive art nouveau Balluta Building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I returned to the hotel to prepare for my presentation the next morning. This went much better than I was expecting with a number of hotline representatives asking me to send them my presentation. After lunch, I went to the airport to catch my flight back. So I didn&#39;t get to see a lot of Malta. I enjoyed the sun and warmth and the somewhat arabic architecture of the buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://inhope.org/EN/articles/inhope-spring-2023-hotline-training-meeting-recap&quot;&gt;recap of the event&lt;/a&gt; is published on the INHOPE website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was insightful and my presentation a success. So overall a good two days away and on the flight back I got a nice view of the alps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/malta-alps.webp&quot; alt=&quot;View of the snow capped Alps through the airplane window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Stroll in the Steinsel woods</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/roman-steinsel/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-23T19:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/roman-steinsel/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A nice little walk in the woods above Steinsel with Angie. I came across &amp;quot;Yet Another Roman Ruin&amp;quot;. Discovered in 1957 apparently. Not sure the columns are actually real. Good for effect though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/roman-steinsel.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Ruins of a Roman site in a wooded area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Goodbye to Wordpress</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wordpress/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-13T09:33:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/wordpress/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I deleted my remaining Wordpress sites and cancelled my Wordpress account. And so ends over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/history/&quot;&gt;13 years of Wordpress hosting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since moving my site to Eleventy, I had kept my two remaining Wordpress sites online only because an old post about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2013/epson-scan-window-wont-open/&quot;&gt;Epson printer window&lt;/a&gt; on one site was still quite popular. But that post no longer got any hits in the last couple of years, so it was OK to turn off the site. That left one remaining site where I had a collected a few paintings of mine. I copied those to this site as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/&quot;&gt;post called Creative Eye&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always liked &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, the internet&#39;s most successful CMS platform. It&#39;s open source nature and the philosophy of it&#39;s creator certainly appealed to me. It was easy to install when self-hosting and easy to use whether self-hosted or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;. And the price point was perfect: $0. Something I blogged about a while back when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2021/netlify-wordpress/&quot;&gt;comparing it to JAMStack sites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in recent years I did find the act of writing a post got more complex than it needed to be. The Guttenberg editor was surely a reason for this. I never quite got the hang of it, even if I could understand the idea behind it. On top of this, the sheer number of options meant it was sometimes hard to find where to do what if you didn&#39;t use the tool regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I say goodbye to Wordpress not because it is a bad choice of CMS, but because I found a setup more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/replacing-forestry/&quot;&gt;suitable for my needs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Creative Eye</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-12T19:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are 12 images copied from an old and now defunct websites of mine: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cr8iveye.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Cr8ive Eye&lt;/a&gt;. Of course that link now no longer works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subtitle of the site: The creative failures of an artistic illeterate! [sic]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-lines.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Lines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Dots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-dots.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Dots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Crosses and Squiggles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/squiggles.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Crosses and Squiggles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/shinkansen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rural Road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rural-road.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rural Road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sunset.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creative Eye&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/creative-eye.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Creative Eye&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blue Vase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/blue-vase.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Vase&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Snake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/snake.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Snake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Three Seasons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/three-seasons.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Three Seasons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angry-birds.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angry Birds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jungle Picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/jungle-picture.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Jungle Picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
