<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2024-06-06T15:28:11Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Testing Git based CMSs</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/testing-git-based-cmss/"/>
		<updated>2024-06-06T15:28:11Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/testing-git-based-cmss/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every now and then I am looking for a better editing experience for my website content. Currently I am simply editing the content either directly in GitHub or else in Visual Studio Code. This is fine, about the only inconvenience is dealing with image uploads: resizing, optimising and adding to the content. The last time I looked into a CMS was about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/alternatives-to-forestry/&quot;&gt;18 months  ago&lt;/a&gt;. My requirements from back then haven&#39;t really changed, although I am now willing to pay for the CMS if it is really going to simplify my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have come across two open source projects which look promising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pagescms.org/&quot;&gt;Pages CMS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sveltia/sveltia-cms&quot;&gt;Sveltia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are in fact quite similar and can be added to a website without needing a real host, they use netlify or cloudflare for the GitHub authentication parts, the rest is client side code. In fact Sveltia is a fork of &lt;a href=&quot;https://decapcms.org/&quot;&gt;Decap CMS&lt;/a&gt;, which itself is a rebrand of the no longer supported Netlify CMS. Both do a nice job of putting a front end on the GitHub experience, but neither seems to fit in too well with my specificities out of the box (eg collections and assets that contain sub folders). Getting them to work through Cloudflare also takes some fiddling, but it does work in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still miss &lt;a href=&quot;https://tina.io/forestry/&quot;&gt;Forestry&lt;/a&gt;, which was replaced by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tina.io/&quot;&gt;Tina.io&lt;/a&gt;, but that is too focussed on Next.js sites for my liking.  I decided to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudcannon.com/&quot;&gt;CloudCannon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://strapi.io/&quot;&gt;Strapi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sanity.io/&quot;&gt;Sanity&lt;/a&gt; another look. But they either had too many proprietary aspects (Sanity), needed to be self hosted (Strapi) or just not quite what i wanted (CloudCannon). I guess I will just have to stick with GitHub and VSC. No harm done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Visiting Tuscany</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/visiting-tuscany/"/>
		<updated>2024-05-26T11:11:11Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/visiting-tuscany/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - Arrival in Pisa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Pisa on time, picked up the rental car and checked into the hotel around 3pm. The hotel, which belonged to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hotel-bb.com/en&quot;&gt;B&amp;amp;B Hotels&lt;/a&gt; chain, did not feel like one. Our room &amp;quot;with terrace&amp;quot; was on the 5th floor, which had to be reached by stairs from the 4th floor. The terrace was rusty and uninviting. The whole thing seemed like an afterthought. This is not the usual basic but solid standard we expected from that chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a rest we headed to Pisa by taxi, which at around 18 Euros was not too pricey and saved the headache and cost of parking. Just in front of the Univerity of Pisa, where none other than Galieo Galilei studied, there was Renault 5 tuning exibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed onto the leaning tower of Pisa and admired the hordes of people taking photos of themselves propping up the tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the evening with a lovely meal at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/vzXSvtuSmE1qFmn58&quot;&gt;Osteria San Sisto&lt;/a&gt; just round the corner of the Renault 5 meet and late evening stroll along the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 - Pisa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we drove to the centre, parking in &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/Xh4NQ4wWfzPj7PyQA&quot;&gt;tower parking&lt;/a&gt;, which is central and reasonably priced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A late breakfast sitting the quiet yard of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/tZvzVSKhVxzwpFuP9&quot;&gt;Caffè dei Cavalieri&lt;/a&gt; was lovely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wander around town took us passed the place where Galileo lived as well as the house were he was born and onto the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-8.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/b1R4AaKMYKbM8vTa8&quot;&gt;National Museum of San Matteo&lt;/a&gt; which was intersting and made a nice quiet respite from the heat and the tourists! I particularly liked this painting by Quentin Metsys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-9.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We followed that with a walk around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://museodellagrafica.sma.unipi.it/&quot;&gt;Museo della Grafica Palazzo Lanfranchi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally at the end of a tiring day, we sat down for dinner in one of the tourist traps along the pedestrian zone. As expected, it was not great. If you want nice food, keep away from the Via Santa Maria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 - Volterra and Siena&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On day three we drove to Siena, via a stopover in Volterra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-10.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a lovely amble around town, visiting the Etruscan museum. This was interesting, but got rather repetitive as it ended up being just etruscan urn after etruscan urn. A bit like doom scrolling on TikTok...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Roman Amphitheatre was nice, although not as nice as the one we are used to in Plovdiv. We had a nice lunch in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/6vNr5NqT1rfmKi6X8&quot;&gt;Irish pub&lt;/a&gt; doubling up as a pizzeria during the day for the tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-11.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished off by having a look at the Medici Fortress, which is not really a tourist attraction, but a medium security prison. Wandering into an open door, we almost got locked in as it started to automatially close behind us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-12.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-13.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed to our apartment in Siena, the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://hotelsienaborgogrondaie.com/&quot;&gt;Borgo Grondaie&lt;/a&gt; and had a reasonable pizza in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/6wKrq2tgxyQepxgF9&quot;&gt;I Gabellieri&lt;/a&gt;. It was pouring down with rain when left the pizzeria. Thankfully that was the last of the really wet weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 4 - Siena&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a slow start to the day and a lunch in the apartment we headed to Siena, leaving the car in the Fortress parking. Siena is very impressive, much more so than Florence. The Campo Plaza, the medieval central square at the centre of town is a view to behold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-14.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearby is also the magnificent Duomo de Siena, who&#39;s interior is as wonderful as the exterior. You can also pay to climb some nearby walls in order to look at the Dome and Siena from above. It&#39;s a wonderful sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-15.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambling around a bit more, when ended up having a rather dissapointing dinner at the Shangai restaurant in town. It did make a change from Italian pizza and pasta though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the apartment in the evening, for a nice glass of local wine in the gardens of the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 5 - Val D&#39;Orcia, Pienza and Terme Rapolano&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove to Pienza, through the beautiful countryside of the Val D&#39;Orcia and some stormy weather. The town has stunning views over the rolling hills of the valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-16.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-17.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-18.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-19.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walked around the town a little, looking for lunch, but instead stumbled through the crew setting up a film shoot. Apparently George Clooney and Adam Sandler are starring in the film. But we didn&#39;t want to hang around too much as the clouds were looking ominous, so we headed off quite soon and rove to Terme Rapolano, again through a few rain showers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Terme Rapolano we stayed for a couple of hours in the San Giovanni Spa which was lovely, including an infinity pool looking out over the beautiful countryside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 6 - Florence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a late start to the day, we drove to Florence, parking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://parcheggiovillacostanza.it/en/&quot;&gt;Villa Costanza&lt;/a&gt;. This is a really well thought out parking allowing tourists to drive to the outskirts of town and then get the tram into the centre. The tram ride took about 25 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in Florence, we saw usual wonderful things, the Cathedral, Palazzio Vecchio, Ufizi gallery (including paintings by Botticelo, Michelangleo, Leonardo) and the Ponte Vecchio. Lunch was a terrible affair and I almost had my bag nabbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-20.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-21.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-22.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-23.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-24.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/tuscany-25.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As lovely as Florence is, there&#39;s just too many tourists there to make it enjoyable. Of course we were tourists ourselves, so we can&#39;t complain. Having had enough of the crowds we headed back to parking on the tram and drove home in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 7 - Spa San Giovanni again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our last full day, so we had a lazy morning doing very little. We did go to the shop to get products for lunch and we did some preparatory packing. In the afternoon we headed off to the Spa Giovanni again for another relaxing afternoon. This time we put on sunscreen so we could catch a tan. Of course it was cloudy with the odd drips of rain. But that did not distract from the relaxing time at the spa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 8 - Return to Pisa and flight home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of our last day we drove off to Pisa airport. I had set Google to take me to a petrol station not too far from the airport, so that I could fuel up the car before dropping it off at the car rental. Google having a mind of it&#39;s own, sent me up a dirt track to get to the petrol station. Expecting me to walk the last 100 metres. Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, all is well that ends well. We got to the airport, dropped off the car, got on the plane and returned home no problem. Two days later I had Covid!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Formulating Questions</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/formulating-questions/"/>
		<updated>2024-05-05T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/formulating-questions/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a few hours over the last couple of days upgrading my eleventy setup to &amp;quot;v3.0 canary&amp;quot;, and then to tidy up my eleventy config file, taking inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;https://eleventy-excellent.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;eleventy-excellent&lt;/a&gt;. The idea being to move all my custom filters, collections, plugins and shortcodes to module files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This went very well, but there were a couple of filters that simply didn&#39;t work. After several hours of failing to fix them, I relented and decided to ask a question in the eleventy GitHub discussions forum. It took me about 20 minutes to draft the question so that I thought it would be clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the third re-reading and final edits, and literally just as I was hovering over the submit button for the final click, the answer jumped out of my text. It was a dead simple, a stupid error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jim Nielsen&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2024/bulletproof-problem-solving/&quot;&gt;Bulletproof Method to Solving Problems&lt;/a&gt; came to mind. I made it right to the very end of Step 1, but not further!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I was going to submit, see if you can spot the problem. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I have upgraded Eleventy to v3.0 canary which has generally worked very well. So I don&#39;t think this is related to that (and probably more to my general lack of knowledge...).
&lt;p&gt;I then moved my custom filters from the eleventy.config.js file to a module file. At this point I got an error for one of the filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The filter is creating a URL link to the file on github and looks like this in the eleventy.config.js file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;eleventyConfig.addFilter(&#39;pathToGitHub&#39;, (localPath) =&amp;gt; {
    let baseURL = &#39;https://github.com/..../blob/master/&#39;;
    let outURL =  new URL(localPath,baseURL);
    return outURL;
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works fine when using the filter like this in my njk file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/robindotis/robin.is/blob/master/posts/2024/formulating-questions.md&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Edit&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Edit&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when I then move this filter into a module and import and add the filter like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;import filters from &amp;quot;./_config/filters.js&amp;quot;;
.
.
export default async function(eleventyConfig) {
    eleventyConfig.addFilter(&amp;quot;pathToGitHub&amp;quot;, filters.folderList);

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get this error when using the filter to create the edit link above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;[11ty] 2. (./_layouts/base.njk)
[11ty]   Template render error: (C:&#92;...&#92;eleventy&#92;robin.is&#92;_includes&#92;footer.njk)
[11ty]   Error: ENOTDIR: not a directory, scandir &#39;C:&#92;...&#92;eleventy&#92;robin.is&#92;pages&#92;home.njk&#39; (via Template render error)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such this error makes sense, since &lt;code&gt;page.inputPath&lt;/code&gt; is not a path to a directory but a file. What I don&#39;t understand is why I get this error when putting the filter in a module, but not when leaving it directly in the eleventy config file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some further trial and error indicates that it is not related to the filter code itself, because even if that filter does nothing (eg simply &lt;code&gt;return &amp;quot;/&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) I get the error. I also don&#39;t get the error without using the filter, ie simply using this (which is obviously pointless):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;./posts/2024/formulating-questions.md&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Edit&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Edit&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the error occurs between the output of &lt;code&gt;page.inputPath&lt;/code&gt; and before its input into &lt;code&gt;pathToGitHub&lt;/code&gt;, but only when that function is in a module.  So there is something in the &amp;quot;module&amp;quot; functionality that I am not understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any suggestions welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Waiting</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/waiting/"/>
		<updated>2024-04-26T09:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/waiting/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My daughter was on a trip in Bosnia and had not been feeling well the final two days. So, I had to pick her up at Frankfurt Airport after the return flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sat outside the arrivals gate, waiting. After the plane had landed it took forever for the display to change to baggage collection. Bored and doom scrolling on my phone, I was waiting for a group of about 40 kids to appear. But my daughter collected her baggage and left as she knew I was already there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She sent me a text about whether I had a new phone. I wondered how she knew that, maybe somehow from my messages. A few seconds later she sent me this photo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/waiting.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&#39;d been sitting next to me for about a minute and I hadn&#39;t noticed! 🤣🤣🤣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My excuse is that I got up at 5am to get to the airport for 8am.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pink Martini</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/pink-martini/"/>
		<updated>2024-04-25T17:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/pink-martini/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A wonderful concert from Pink Martini at the Rockhal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/pink-martini.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Global Age Assurance Summit Manchester</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/age-assurance-summit-manchester/"/>
		<updated>2024-04-11T17:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/age-assurance-summit-manchester/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week I was in Manchester for three days to give a presentation on the &amp;quot;EU approach to age assurance and age verification&amp;quot;, at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.ringcentral.com/events/global-age-assurance-standards-summit/registration&quot;&gt;Global Age Assurance Summit&lt;/a&gt;. My 15 minute presentation went well and there were plenty of questions afterwards to fill the remaining 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was interesting, showing the amount of effort that is going into keeping children safe online. This is something that should have been happening 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Parrain</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/parrain/"/>
		<updated>2024-04-07T22:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/parrain/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My uncle died on the 29th March. He was cremated on the 5th April. That was the day we returned from our holidays. So upon landing in Brussels Charleroi, we got off the plane and headed for the crematorium to attend the service in the afternoon. We missed the church service in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his memory, I have added the name we called him by, Parrain, to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnuterrypratchett.com/&quot;&gt;GNU Terry Pratchett&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;X-Clacks-Overhead&amp;quot; header on my website. This ensures his name is passed around the internet for as long this site is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&quot;A man is not dead while his name is still spoken.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Going Postal, Chapter 4 prologue&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Shattered Nation</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/shattered-nation/"/>
		<updated>2024-03-19T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/shattered-nation/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Danny Dorling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very interesting book about high inequality within the UK, apparently the highest in Europe except for Bulgaria. It&#39;s quite a depressing read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One caveat: the book does compare the UK badly to the rest of Europe, especially the similarly wealthy western / northern countries. I am not convinced that these countries are doing much better. The author does point this out, but is also clear: in his view, whilst things are bad in other places, in almost none of them are they as bad as the UK - not even close. I can&#39;t help feeling though that they are going full steam ahead in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is centred on the five identified in The Beveridge report (from 1942) which lead to the creation of the NHS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;want – an adequate income for all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;disease – access to health care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignorance – a good education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;squalor – adequate housing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;idleness – gainful employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK, having brilliantly managed to almost erradicate these evils by the 1970s, becoming the most equal country in Europe, with the best healthcare and social policies, is now back sliding. Policies since then, from all political parties, have brought the five evils back in a different form. Their modern equivalents are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hunger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;precarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book makes some very good points on the ruling classes being completely out of touch with rest of the population and therefore unable to understand the reality of these five modern evils. For example around 80% of economics students are from a privileged background. These are the ones creating policies to alleviate things like hunger. Only veterinary science has a higher percentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book contains many obvious observations that are either poorly understood by economists or ignored because it would reduce their own wealth. Such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price mechanism works quite well for goods such as clothes because there are few monopoly supplies and people become quite expert at buying clothes as they do it often. People rarely become expert at buying a university education or a heart operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting point is made in chapter 5 on waste. More and more people are working in services that are essentially supporting the wealthy to manage and increase their wealth. Outside of remuneration, this sort of work creates no real value to the person doing it. Nor to society as a whole. These people&#39;s significant skills are not put to work on anything truly meaningful, like helping others, creating joy and happines or even simply making things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By judging a job&#39;s worth only through its financial value we devalue what is truly meaningful and what actually adds to the greater good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I have often thought about myself. The financialisation of almost every aspect of public life, means that the decisions on whether to provide tax payer support are made purely on whether it is directly profitable. No thought is given whether it is simply useful in helping people go about their lives in a meaningful way. Where&#39;s the direct profit in saving someone&#39;s life, or cleaning the streets. Where&#39;s the profit in healthy people not needing medications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once, this is also a book that does not end with a positive call for arms (well, it pushes that to the acknowledgements...). Instead it points to what could happen if something doesn&#39;t change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is even possible that inequalities could fall within the large majority of the population, while rising overall because just a tiny few at the top are allowed to keep taking more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 19/02/2024. Finished 19/03/2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/shattered-nation.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;296&quot; height=&quot;445&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Kopstal Circular Walk - Again</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/kopstal-circular-walk/"/>
		<updated>2024-03-17T14:52:47Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/kopstal-circular-walk/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By chance I repeated this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/kopstal-circular-walk&quot;&gt;walk I had completed a couple years ago&lt;/a&gt;. Back then I noted it it down as a 6km walk, but it seems they have added a kilometre as it is now a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitluxembourg.com/tour/circular-walk-kopstal&quot;&gt;7km around the wooded hills of kopstal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sure I came across two ponds for Angie to jump in and make a mess of herself, which weren&#39;t there last time. Otherwise my thoughts on the walk are the same as back then, although it was a little quieter since it was a Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/kopstal2-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/kopstal2-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/kopstal2-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/kopstal2-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/kopstal2-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Spectrum Vocal Band</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/spectrum/"/>
		<updated>2024-03-02T21:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/spectrum/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A fun evening watching the Bulgarian a cappella group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/spectrumvocalband&quot;&gt;Spectrum&lt;/a&gt; in Luxembourg, gratefully organised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/clubgaida/&quot;&gt;Club Gaida&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly liked their interpretation of California Dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/spectrum-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/spectrum-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
