<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>robin.is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-02-19T22:18:27Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Sveta Petka</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/sveta-petka/"/>
		<updated>2023-02-19T22:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/sveta-petka/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Twenty years after my last walk to Sveta Petka monastery in the hills above Asenovgrad, I did the same again. This is a religious day specific to the monastery and it started appropriately by saving the life of a dog. This poor chap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sveta-petka-dog.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Dog resting in dried grass in front of a monastery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;had fallen into a reservoir and couldn&#39;t climb out of the water due to the steep smooth concrete banks. So the tallest guy in our group, held by two others, climbed over the barrier and pulled the dog out of the water. We gave the dog some bread and went on our way up the steep hill to the monastery. At the top we saw the dog resting in front of the official ceremony of the monastery. Holy dog indeed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sveta Petka monastery is known for being a hiding place for Bulgarian revolutionary, Vasil Levski. I saw his hiding place 20 years ago, so didn&#39;t queue this timee to see it, but the monastery itself is reasonably well maintained, with on-going construction works and well worth a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We carried on past the monastery, through masses of people and found a spot about about a few hundred metres further along. Actually, we didn&#39;t find it, it&#39;s where the group always has their picnic on this hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I got there the others had already started the fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sveta-petka-fire.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Log fire for BBQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wine and rakia started flowing and soon those more musical than me started dancing the &amp;quot;Horo&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sveta-petka-horo.webp&quot; alt=&quot;People line dancing the Horo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having relaxed in that spot for several hours, we continued on to catch the last of the sunset and then headed down the steep and rocky path with our head torches. After a quick stop at a rock called &amp;quot;Anathem&amp;quot;, we continued on to the little &amp;quot;Sveta Petka&amp;quot; church with this lovely view of the town half way down the hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sveta-petka-cross.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cross lit up at night with Asenovgrad glowing in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a great day out. The last time I had done this hike was in snow with sub zero temperatures 20 years ago. This time it was 20°C. I guess this is climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what it looked like 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sveta-petka-2003.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Me sitting on a rock in the snow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Frameworks</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/frameworks/"/>
		<updated>2023-02-15T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/frameworks/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across a couple of posts about the usefullness of JavaScript frameworks, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://vuejs.org/&quot;&gt;Vue&lt;/a&gt;. Their promise is to simplify the creation of modern web applications. These discussions seem to kick off every now and then in the same way that 20 years ago people debated Java vs .Net and 40 years ago it was probably C vs Perl. The current debate is often centered around the speed of the pages using frameworks, which are bulkier and slower than native rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://infrequently.org/2023/02/the-market-for-lemons/&quot;&gt;the market for lemons&lt;/a&gt;, Alex wrote a very good description of how these frameworks are knowingly over selling their benefits (faster development, easier to maintain, better support, access to a arger developer pool). A key takeaway for me was that these frameworks do give significant benefits to large teams able to invest and maintain in them. Smaller teams however, tend to get bogged down in their complexity the moment you go beyond the defaults. It&#39;s a bit like the &amp;quot;blog in five minutes&amp;quot; use cases that popped up all over the place when &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/a&gt; turned up 20 years ago. Of course RoR was truly revolutionary at the time and incredibly powerful, but the same was not true for other frameworks of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Laurie posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://seldo.com/posts/the_case_for_frameworks&quot;&gt;the case for frameworks&lt;/a&gt; in support of React and JavaScript frameworks. His main argument, whilst acknowlegding certain failings of frameworks, is that you&#39;re OK because everyone is doing it. This is the 2020s reload of the &amp;quot;no one ever got fired for picking IBM&amp;quot; thinking in the 80s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But are these frameworks as popular as they seem. Andy takes a look his post &lt;a href=&quot;https://andy-bell.co.uk/the-extremely-loud-minority/&quot;&gt;the (extremely) loud minority&lt;/a&gt; and concludes &amp;quot;not really&amp;quot;. Obviously there are thousands of sites using React, but only 3.3% of the top 10 million websites actually use it. The percentage of all websites is probably much smaller. In comparison, Wordpress is used by 43.1% of the top 10 million websites. The reason these frameworks seem more popular than they actually is explained in &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/journal/15011&quot;&gt;dev perception&lt;/a&gt; by Jeremy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt; is still used on over 77% of the top 10 million websites. 16 years after it&#39;s first release. It&#39;s popularity is only now starting to dip. There are many reasons for it&#39;s popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason is that jQuery was released at a time when web standards were poorly supported by browsers. This meant developers had to write code for each of the common browsers at the time. jQuery provided a standardising layer, which enabled your code to work well in all browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second is that it was not released by a big tech company. jQuery was created by one guy, John Resig. Since there was no big company owning jQuery, other companies didn&#39;t feel the need to compete and release their own framework. There was no competition and it quickly became the defacto framework used by anyone programming front-end JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third reason is that jQuery was quite simple to get started with. You could sprinkle it lightly throughout your code, or you could base all your code around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for it&#39;s recent dip: browsers are finally more or less equal in terms of standars support and the use case for jQuery is waning, especially in new projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this leads me to the actual point I want to make. It&#39;s about the most common framework, used by 100% of all websites. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WorldWideWeb&quot;&gt;work in progress since 1990&lt;/a&gt;. It is of course the browser using standard HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Sure, it doesn&#39;t always have the latest bells and whistles like, instead its future support is unparalled. It will never be obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&#39;t go wrong choosing it. In fact you can&#39;t avoid choosing it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Safer Internet Day - 2023</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/safer-internet-day-2023/"/>
		<updated>2023-02-10T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/safer-internet-day-2023/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tuesday 7th February was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saferinternetday.org/&quot;&gt;Safer Internet Day&lt;/a&gt; in 2023. It also marks the 20th year of the initiative, which is supported by the European Commission through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/safer-internet-day&quot;&gt;Safer Internet team of DG CONNECT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of that day, we arranged a morning in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmrl.lu/&quot;&gt;Lycee Michel-Rodange&lt;/a&gt; in Luxembourg City, to let a class of the school try out the latest VR headsets from Meta. The kids, all around 15 years of age, got to try out five different VR worlds as they circulated around different stands in a class room. After that they had a brief discussion, giving their thoughts on VR in their futures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long time since I was in a class room full of 15 year olds and it was incredibly energising. They were all well behaved, whilst having their fun with the headsets. Maybe that is the Luxembourg effect!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of all, in my opinion, was the lack of enthusiasm for this technology with these kids. Our polling showed they did not believe this technology would become an alternate world for them in the future. Whilst they saw the use of it in certain educational situations, few would be interested VR being their main medium of education. Despite growing up with always connected smartphones, they still apparently wanted face to face contact with their friends. They certainly didn&#39;t want to live in the VR world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own take on this, having tried out the headsets, is that they are simply not ready for the mainstream. The technology is too fiddly and, despite being relatively easy to use, is too cumbersome to do what appear to be basic things. I certainly can&#39;t see the advantage over a physical meeting with colleagues, or even a video-conference. There&#39;s still a long way to go before this tech can become mainstream. Maybe it never will, at least not in this form. And certainly not for entertainment or socialising purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calm before the storm:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/PXL_20230210_074201645.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Empty class room ready to receive kids to try out headsets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the VR begin:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/PXL_20230210_093540947.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Class room full of teenagers trying out the VR headsets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>European Bac choices toolkkit</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/bac-choices/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-31T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/bac-choices/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this week my younger daughter has to have chosen the subjects she wants to study for her European Baccalaureate. For those in the UK, this is equivalent to choosing your A levels, but much more complicated. This i not to say that it is easier, since these are always difficult choices. Just that there are subjects that are compulsory and more rules about which combination of subjects are not allowed. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.euroschool.lu/site/secondary-s6-s7-subject-choice-booklet/#1575669389394-aa74a39f-b3ba&quot;&gt;exact rules can be found here&lt;/a&gt;, but since that link is likely to break in the future, I recap them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Compulsory subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must take a number of compulsory subjects, which are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 1, 4 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 2, 3 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maths: either 3 or 5 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biology 2 periods
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unless Biology, Physics or Chemisty are taken as 4 period subjects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geography 2 periods
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unless taken as a 4 period subject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History 2 periods
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unless taken as a 4 period subject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philiosophy 2 periods
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unless taken as a 4 period subject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethics 1 period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Education 2 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Optional subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addtion you must choose a minimum of 2 and a maximum of 4 optional 4 period subjects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemistry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economics or Latin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 4 or ONL (Other National Language)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Advanced subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also choose one advanced subject from the three available (in addition to their normal level):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Language 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Language 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Maths
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only if Maths 5 period is chosen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From all of the above (compulsory, optional and advanced), you must have a minimum of 29 periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Complementary subjects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also choose a range of complementary subjects, which are 2 periods each. I won&#39;t list them all here except that ones that have conditions attached to them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laboratory in Biology, Physics or Chemistry
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can only choose one of these and only if you are doing the equivalent 4 period subject&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Economics
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot be chosen if you have chosen 4 period economics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Total periods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of your chosen subjects must amount to at least 31 periods and maximum 35 periods. You can go slightly higher, but this needs permission from the school. You cannot go lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final exam choices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above has important ramnifications for the subjects you are examined in at the end of the Bac. All the subjects count towards your bac, but those you choose to be examined in count much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot choose complementary subjects for these exams. If you choose one of the advanced subjects you must be examined in it. In addition there are written and oral exams, some of which cannot be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the written exams, of which you take five, your choices are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compulsory: Language 1 (or advanced if taken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compulsory: Language 2 (or advanced if taken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compulsory: Maths 3 or 5 period (depending on which you chose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choice from:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of the 4 period subjects you have chosen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition you cannot choose for the oral exams a subject you chose as one your choices for the 4 period subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the oral exams, of which you take three, your choices are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compulsory: Language 1 (or advanced if taken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choice from:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language 2 (or advanced if taken)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced is compulsory if chosen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History 2 or 4 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geography 2 or 4 periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choice from:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most of the other 4 period subjects, unless chosen as the second option above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explain all this because it means you might end up with no choices in the exams you have to take, depending on your subject choices for the bac. But understanding this can be quite complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I coded up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/html/bac-choices.html&quot;&gt;european bac subject toolkit&lt;/a&gt; to help my daughter visualise the consequences of her subject choices on the final bac exams she will have to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I coded the entire toolkit without resorting to any frameworks or external scripts. These would have taken me much longer to learn than simply using vanilla JavaScript. What is good to see is how far in built browser support for lots of JavaScript functionality has come.  For this little toolkit using any kind of framework would have been complete overkill.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>inABLE</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inable/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-25T17:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inable/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Training kids in assistive technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a webinar organised by ARSO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arso-oran.org/&quot;&gt;the African Organisation for Standardisation&lt;/a&gt;, there was a speaker from &lt;a href=&quot;https://inable.org/&quot;&gt;Inable&lt;/a&gt;. This is a charity setup to train children with disabilities to use assistive technology and to provide them necessary digital skills to live an independent life in the modern world. They have a very nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://inable.org/about-us/our-story/&quot;&gt;video on the use of assistive technology&lt;/a&gt; in every day life.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dog on a log - in winter</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-yet-again/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-19T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dog-on-a-log-yet-again/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This time I had to put her on the log, because after jumping up she kept on sliding off and eventually couldn&#39;t be bothered to jump back on again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/dog-log-winter.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Dog sitting on a frosted log in winter forest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2021/dog-log/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Autumn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/dog-on-a-log-again/&quot;&gt;Dog on a log in Summer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Parable of the Talents</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/parable-of-the-talents/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-09T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/parable-of-the-talents/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Octavia E. Butler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The follow up book to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/parable-of-the-sower/&quot;&gt;Parable of the Sower&lt;/a&gt;. This is a fantastic read, possibly better still than the preceding novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story continues with the heroine trying to setup her Earthseed religion, but ending up enslaved, having her baby daughter taken from her before finally succeeding and her daughter finding her many years later. It might seem like a happy ending, but it is not so simple with internal family and religious feuds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the name of the book, it is interesting to discuss which of the main characters is representing which of the servants in the biblical story of the same name as told in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parable_of_the_talents_or_minas#Parable_of_the_Talents&quot;&gt;Mathew 25:14-30&lt;/a&gt;. Or maybe such a link is not intended by the author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is also remarkably prescient of today&#39;s world, climate change, the religious right and especially of the years with Trump as president. Whilst we have avoided the apocalypse so far, the problems have not disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/talents.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ski pistes in climate change</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/ski-pistes/"/>
		<updated>2023-01-08T07:30:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/ski-pistes/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were up in Pamporovo recently, staying at the lovely &lt;a href=&quot;https://malina-pamporovo.com/en/&quot;&gt;Villa Malina&lt;/a&gt;. I don&#39;t ski, so I&#39;ve never really seen ski pistes in the winter. There was no snow at all in the surrounding mountains. Yet a piste was there, created with artificial snow and being used by a lot of skiers. I know know how they market these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The marketing blurb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;White ski piste cutting through the forest in the hills&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Looking on to the back of Skiers just before they go over the edge of the ski slope&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;View over the mountains with no snow except for the white ski pistes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;View of the radio tower at Snejanka, with blue sky background and brown fields in the foreground, except for the ski piste&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;View over the snowless mountains from the top of the tower. In the far distance there are snow topped mountains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Villa Malina&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The moutain chalets at night lit up by lights on their terrace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ski-piste-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A set of mountain chalets overlooked by tall pine trees behind them and dry grass in the foreground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Clacks Overhead</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/clacks-overhead/"/>
		<updated>2022-12-31T12:59:59Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/clacks-overhead/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discworld author Terry Pratchett died in 2015. His books were hugely popular, making him one of the most successfull authors of all time. To remember him, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/discworld/comments/2yt9j6/gnu_terry_pratchett/&quot;&gt;group of redditers&lt;/a&gt; came up with the idea of implementing the clacks  system from the book Going Postal in today&#39;s internet. This can done by adding the following bit of code to the &lt;code&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; tag in any HTML file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-Clacks-Overhead&quot; content=&quot;GNU Terry Pratchett&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can also be implemented by configuring web servers to send an appropriate page header. In fact this is the better option, but I am not able to configure the web server, as I am using GitHub Pages to host the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had implemented this years ago, whilst I still had my site running on Wordpress. After moving to a static site, I had forgotten about this and not added the clacks meta tag. Well, now it&#39;s back - just in time for the new year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the clacks headers is available here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnuterrypratchett.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.gnuterrypratchett.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site also lists a number of plugins which can notify you if you are visiting a site which has implemented the clacks header.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Look to Windward</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/look-to-windward/"/>
		<updated>2022-12-30T22:11:11Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/look-to-windward/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the easier to read culture novels. Told in an intersting way and without a predictable outcome whilst reading it, nor a clear answer to who did (or didn&#39;t) do it. What continues to impress is the way Iain M Banks is able to really drill home timeless infinity that defines our galaxy and the universe beyond it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The culture, whilst one of the more advanced and expansive civilisations in the galaxy, are portrayed as really just in their mid-20s. Very clever and important, but really not quite able to compete with those even more advanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/windward.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
