<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>robin.is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-04-13T03:32:05Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Creative Eye</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-13T03:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/creative-eye/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are 12 images copied from an old and now defunct websites of mine: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cr8iveye.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Cr8ive Eye&lt;/a&gt;. Of course that link now no longer works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subtitle of the site: The creative failures of an artistic illeterate! [sic]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Lines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-lines.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Lines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coloured Dots&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/coloured-dots.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Coloured Dots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Crosses and Squiggles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/squiggles.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Crosses and Squiggles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shinkansen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/shinkansen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Shinkansen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rural Road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rural-road.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rural Road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sunset.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creative Eye&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/creative-eye.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Creative Eye&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blue Vase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/blue-vase.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Vase&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Snake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/snake.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Snake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Three Seasons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/three-seasons.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Three Seasons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angry-birds.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angry Birds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jungle Picture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/jungle-picture.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Jungle Picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Easter Weekend in Istanbul</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/easter-in-istanbul/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-11T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/easter-in-istanbul/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in March &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flypgs.com/en&quot;&gt;Pegasus airlines&lt;/a&gt; opened a new route from Plovdiv to Istanbul, so we thought we would give it a go when we went to Plovdiv for the Easter holidays. I booked some tickets €70 return per person which seemed a reasonable price. I also booked the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tr/sapphire.html&quot;&gt;Sapphire Hotel&lt;/a&gt; for three nights in the Fatih area of Istanbul, right next door to the Topkapi Palace, Ayasofya Mosque and the Sultanahmet Mosque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our flight landed on time in Sabiha Gökcen airport and we proceeded to the exit of gate 13 where the hotel said we will find our pre-booked transfer. What a welcome to Turkey that was! We found the right location, but there were many others looking for a transfer at the same location and we were approached by several drivers offering a transfer, none of whom seemed to know our name or our destination. Not having roaming, I was unable to contact the hotel. After some standing around, looking like useless tourists (which we were), we eventually managed to get a transfer for €45, which was €5 less than the hotel had stated us. And so began our adrenalin fueled taxi ride from another dimension...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got in the cab and set off, a short while later the cab driver pulled into a nearby petrol station to refuel. Not for petrol as you might expect, but for RedBull and cigarettes. And so the fun began. More thrilling than a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vdl.lu/fr/node/11240&quot;&gt;Schueberfouer&lt;/a&gt; ride, more dangerous than a shuttle launch and more scary than a Stephen King movie: our taxi driver was weaving in and out of traffic on the motorway into town, whilst holding a can of RedBull in one hand, a cigarette in the other, speaking to god knows who on one phone and using Google translate to give me the tourist highlights on another all whilst changing gears with the wrong hand. After too many &amp;quot;beyond close&amp;quot; calls with other cars on the road, including several where I thought &amp;quot;that was a nice life, unfortunatrly didn&#39;t quite make it to 50&amp;quot;, we promptly hit peak traffic around our hotel and didn&#39;t move for a good 20 minutes whilst we were a 15 minutes walk from our hotel! After several more twists and turns to get passed multiple cars on streets too narrow for even one car, the driver stopped, pulled in between two traffic cones and said: &amp;quot;this as close as I can get you, your hotel is down that road first on your left&amp;quot;. So we got out, I gave a €5 tip and we got to our hotel a few minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - Easter Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started off on this cold, but sunny day, by walking around Gülhane park which is next to Topkapi palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/gulhane-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Gülhane Sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tulips had been planted in the park for Istanbul&#39;s Tulip festival which is in the whole month of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/gulhane-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Gulhane Tulips&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the northern end of the park we had a look at the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/bosphorus.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Bosphorus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed back to the entrance of the Topkapi palace. Unfortunately the queues were so long we headed on to the Ayasofya Mosque only to be confronted by even longer queues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/ayasofya.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Ayasofya Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to be dispirited, we continued on to the Sultanahmet Mosque only to see that it was temporarily closed for restoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sultanahmet.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sultanahment Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would explain why the other two queues were so long. That and the fact the place was full of Easter weekend tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed onto the Mosaic Museum, via a nice market, but that was also shut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/spice-stall.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Market stall selling spice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now it was time for lunch, which we had on a roof top terrace that afforded great views of both the Bosphorus and the Sultanahmet Mosque. The food was also very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/sultanahmet-rooftop.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Sultanahmet from roof top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having relaxed a bit on the terrace we headed to the spice market on the other side of the Fatih quarter. Whilst interesting, spice wasn&#39;t the only thing they sold here, which made it feel like just another market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/spice-market.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Spice market&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having failed to get into any of the mosques in the Topkapi palace area, we were happy to have a look inside the Yeni Mosque, just next to the spice market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/yeni-mosque.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yeni Mosque&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we could also see the Galata tower and were discussing on the merits of getting the tram across the bridge or walking when a guy managed to convince us to get on a one hour cruise around the Bosphorus. He gave us about 50% off the regular price, which we later realised was because it was probably the last cruise of the day and the boat was quite empty. Still, this meant we got good views as we sailed up and down a section of the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the riverside views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/galata-tower.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Galata Tower&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/yeni-rustem-mosques.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yeni and Rüstem Pasha mosques&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/asian-side-flag-tower.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Asian side with the largest mosque, flag and tower&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/flags.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Flags&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 - Easter Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second day in Istanbul was essentially a day of cold and rain. The good thing about this was that it forced us to figure out the public transport and the benefits of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://istanbulepass.com/how-to-get-istanbul-kart.html&quot;&gt;Istanbul Card&lt;/a&gt;. The card costs 50TL and using it you get roughly half price fares compared to the regular fare. The best part being that you can share the card between five people, so no need to spend 200TL for the family just on cards. By sharing the card between the four of us, we recuperated the cost of the card after a couple of journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we headed to Taksim square first on the tram and then up the hill with the funicular (which is a regular part of the public transport system and not a tourist thing). As it hadn&#39;t stopped raining, we stopped off in a nearby cafe for an hour or so and had a nice Turkish coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/taksim-square.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Taksim Square&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once it had more or less stopped raining we carried on walking through Taskim park, passed the technical university and down the hill along the Beshiktas football stadium and back to where we got off the tram. Since we hadn&#39;t yet been to the asian part (except for our mad taxi drive at the beginning) we got the ferry to the other side of the Bosphorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beshiktas-stadium.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Beshiktas Stadium&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the asian side we walked north-east along the riverside in the Üsküdar district. Then we walked up the hill through a little park and back down to the ferry station along the main road. This gave us a better feel for what might be the more normal Istanbul away from the maddening tourist crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/uskundar-park.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Üsküdar park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned back to the Fatih district on the Marmaray train. This was an efficient, if dull, experience. It got us back to Fatih in about 3 minutes! Having spent the day getting around on various forms of public transport (tram, funicular, boat and train) I have to say that I am impressed with the public transport in this city. Still the roads are blocked full of cars! Maybe the day to day experience of public transport is different to the tourist one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended the day with a lovely meal in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/saluteistanbul/&quot;&gt;Salute Restaurant&lt;/a&gt;, 100 metres from our hotel. Definitely recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fruit-salad.webp&quot;&gt;Desert fruit salad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 - Return home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our flight home was in the late afternoon and checkout was at midday, so we walked around the Topkapi area in the hope of there being no queues after the easter weekend. We were mistaken, but did manage to get into the Sultan Ahmed Tomb which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/tomb.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Tomb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we headed back to the hotel, grabbed our bags and got in the pre-booked taxi back to the airport. This time it was a normal drive along the motorway. No thrills, no danger, no scares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/bridge-taxi.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge from Taxi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-09T09:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th April is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today my site is naked.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Folkdance Ensemble Trakia</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-07T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely evening, this time watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trakia-ensemble.org/en/&quot;&gt;folkdance ensemble Trakia&lt;/a&gt; perform at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://domborishristov.com/&quot;&gt;House of culture in Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Beebop Plovdiv</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-06T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lovely evening watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/hotclubdeplovdiv/&quot;&gt;Hot Club de Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beebopcafe.tv/&quot;&gt;Beebop Cafe in Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beebop-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beebop-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Upgrading to Eleventy 2</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/eleventy-2-upgrade/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-30T09:12:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/eleventy-2-upgrade/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning I upgraded this site to be generated using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/blog/eleventy-v2/&quot;&gt;Eleventy 2.0.1&lt;/a&gt;. The process was dead simple thanks to this great &lt;a href=&quot;https://danabyerly.com/notes/upgrading-to-eleventy-2-0-0/&quot;&gt;post by Dana Byerly about the upgrade process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however encounter one strange problem with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lodash.com/&quot;&gt;lodash&lt;/a&gt;. After following the first three steps and then running the build command I received errors from npm about the missing &amp;quot;lodash&amp;quot; module. So I looked in my local node_modules and the only relevant folder there was &amp;quot;lodash.deburr&amp;quot;. I am not sure why, or even what the difference is between the two. Possibly this was something which worked in eleventy 1.0 but no longer in eleventy 2.0, no idea. So I ran &lt;code&gt;npm install lodash&lt;/code&gt; and then continued with step 4 and everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I need to see how to take advantage of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://11ty.rocks/posts/new-features-upgrade-considerations-eleventy-version-2/&quot;&gt;new features in Eleventy 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/usage/incremental/&quot;&gt;incremental builds&lt;/a&gt; during development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Follow the Money</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/follow-the-money/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-28T14:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/follow-the-money/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Paul Johnson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/follow-the-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an easy to follow whirlwind tour of where the UK government gets its money from and how it spends it. Full of facts and figures as well as some insightful commentary and significant critiscism of past taxation decisions across all parties. The biggest one being the lack of consistency, closely followed by lack of foresight and unwillngness to challenge current vested interests to improve the future of the country overall. Note that the latter is less about big business and lobbying and more about not wanting to upset the electorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely worth a read as it won&#39;t take you long. It took me a week. But what is missing is any real solution to these problems. Politicians have to win elections every few years so taking decisions which make some people poorer in the short term, but others better off in the long term is hard if you want to be re-elected. This conunmdrum is not solved by the book, which finishes with lots of good tips none of which will necessarily lead to an election victory in the current political climate. It finishes with the simple comment &amp;quot;must do better if we are to cope with the next crisis&amp;quot;. (Which, according to the book is going to be the climate crisis hitting at the same time as a really ageing population comes along.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there was one point which I didn&#39;t quite agree with. In the discussion on student loans the book compared the current loan system to the new one being brought in from September 2023. In the current system, the student loan increases at RPI + 3%, the threshold above which you have to repay at 9% is £27,500 and the loan is written off after 30 years. The estimate was that about 25% would repay their loan in full. In the new system the loan increases with RPI only, the threshold is £25,000 (and increases with RPI from 2025) and your loan is written off after 40 years. Paul&#39;s comparison of these two systems made the point that the old system was actually fairer because it penalises higher earners more. With the loan increasing above RPI higher earners are going to be repaying more overall in monetary terms than in the new system.This is because they will be repaying for longer as the amount owed increases quicker. Whereas for lower earners it doesn&#39;t matter because the amount owed is cleared after 30 years no matter how much was repaid. In the new system the amount owed does not increase so quickly, so higher earners will pay off their loan quicker and therefore pay less overall whereas lower earners will pay more because it is now 40 years before the loan is wiped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis is obviously correct, but there is one point not mentioned at this point in the book. And that is the relative parental wealth of higher vs lower earners. I found this strange because otherwise the book is generally covering wealth aspects well, often making the point that tax should be equitable and the wealthy should be taxed more, when this makes economic sense. I feel the analysis of the current system is wrong, because higher earners mostly come from wealthier backgrounds so it is more likely that their university fees will simply have been covered by their parents, putting them completely outside of the loan system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Matter</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/matter/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-19T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/matter/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 8th book in Iain M Banks&#39; series of Culture novels. It took me 2 and half months to slog through this book. Somehow I could not get into it eventhough the idea behind the Shellworlds is quite incredible. What I do like about the Culture novels is that even if the plot is not your thing, each book reveals a little more about the galaxy within which the Culture civilisation operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story itself is OK in this book, perhaps not one of the better culture series storylines, but stil enjoyable. However it was not always captivating enough to keep me going. So I ended up putting it down for weeks at a time. I seemed to read it in spurts, including the last 100 pages on a Friday afternoon when work was slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best summary of this book I&#39;ve seen is &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/printSF/comments/wjou9/comment/c5dyx5d/&quot;&gt;Matter lacked substance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/matter.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Website carbon calculator</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/carbon-calculator/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-14T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/carbon-calculator/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/&quot;&gt;Website Carbon Calculator&lt;/a&gt; each view of this site&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/website/robin-is/&quot;&gt;homepage produces 0.07g of CO2&lt;/a&gt;. It is therefore cleaner than 94% of web pages tested. Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing with other sites, it seems like the main component of this calculation is filesize. The homepage is about 300kB, depending on how many images happen to be on it. The biggest permanent component is the font file, which is 134kB and therefore contributes over a third of the CO2 prodcued by this homepage without actually contributing much to the function and usability of the site. Is the font file necessary? Perhaps I should switch back to using Arial? It&#39;s interesting how seemingly innocent design choices can have such an impact on the environment. For now it will stay as pretty much no one looks at this site.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/css-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-03T09:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/css-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th April is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparation for this, have updated my &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/robindotis/54786199b5d86f5085e5c55337d6e0d0&quot;&gt;theme picker&lt;/a&gt; to incldue a hard coded &amp;quot;Naked&amp;quot; CSS theme. If desired, this theme will be forced on CSS Naked Day, with no alternative for the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
