<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-12-31T23:00:33Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Can&#39;t we just print more money</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-31T23:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Rupal Patel and Jack Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A book on introductory economics written by employees of the The Bank of England. Very easy to read and generally easy to follow. Understanding some of the theory without some background knowledge of economics might be difficult though. The book could have paid more attention to explaining some of the terminology and concepts. Still it is a good book to get a better understanding of some of the everyday questions on economics you might have. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What causes recessions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is inflation and is it good or bad?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are banks useful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should governments be in debt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the book&#39;s title: Can&#39;t we just print more money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some criticism is due because it tends to support the status quo, along the lines of &amp;quot;it is what it is&amp;quot;. It is honest enough to stress that economics is not a real science and very much hit and miss. It also finishes with a &amp;quot;call to arms&amp;quot;, trying to get more people interested in economics in order to shake up the status quo. More discussions on some of the social consequences of the choices available to governments, banks and economists would have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the different types of taxes that can be raised and from whom. Taxing the very rich or companies has very different consequences to taxing the poor. If the aim is to keep money in the system, then there needs to be a way to limit the very rich from taking it out of the system and put it in offshore bank accounts for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the US can run much larger debt ratio than other countries, because of its political and military importance. Similarly, Japan has the highest debt ratio in the world, but this is not a problem because much of it is held by its citizens and generally the world trusts Japan to repay its debt. So again, like taxes, not all debt is equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book does hint at these sorts of questions in the conclusion and it is intended as an introduction, not a study. It also mentions that most of the public does not understand the consequences of the economic policies they are voting for. Addressing things like taxation and debt in more detail, but still in plain language, might have been useful in achieving the goals of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Count Zero</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-23T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count Zero is the follow on book to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;, which I read last month. It took me a little longer to finish, so I think I missed some of the detail. It was an interesting read, possibly more so even than Neuromancer, although not as ground breaking. I think I will have to re-read this one in a shorter time frame to make more sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 13/11/2023. Finished 22/12/2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/count-zero.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Angie&#39;s Christmas Tale</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-20T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, walking Angie in one of the locations we rarely go to, Angie disappeared. I was walking ahead as usual, she was dilly dallying at the back. When I retraced my steps to go and find her, she was gone. After about half an hour of whistling and shouting I started to get quite worried. I went back to the car to see if she was there, then I called my wife to come back from work to help find her. I also called a nearby neighbour who I know from walking our dogs. She came and helped look with her dog, Tashi. But all to no good. She phoned her bedsitter to check if Angie had returned to our house. No luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neighbour went back to the village, and opened the gate to our garden so Angie could go in, if she returned. At that time my wife had returned home as well and between them half the village was now looking for Angie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I went back to my car and drove down the hill to the houses below where we were walking. This was about 90 minutes after she went missing. Walking around there, a lady came out of one of the houses, asking if I was looking for a dog. I said yes, and she mentioned that another lady, a teacher, had found a dog and put her in her van and gone to work at the school. The teacher had given the lady her phone number. So I got in touch with the teacher and started heading to the school she worked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out the teacher had already posted a message on Facebook which our direct neighbour had already seen, recognised Angie, contacted the teacher separately and was heading to the school with my wife. I followed along and we were reunited with Angie about two and half hours after she went missing. They&#39;d even cleaned her! I guess dirty dogs are not allowed in schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very nice to see how quickly things can come together when everyone helps - and how social media can actually be put to good use as well from time to time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is my Christmas Tale for 2023. 🎅🎄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angies-christmas-tale.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angie waiting to be picked up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Progressive Web App</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-09T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to make my website installable, so it can be added to a device as an installed application. The way to do this is to add some javascript to the site so that it is a Progressive Web App (PWA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a PWA, a website needs only one thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.dev/learn/pwa/service-workers/&quot;&gt;service worker&lt;/a&gt;. Adding one is fairly straightforward, once you know how. It does require a good understanding of asynchronous JavaScript, something which I struggle with. The alternative is just to copy someone else&#39;s service worker code and adapt if needed. I chose the alternative. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I copied the one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt;. It took me a while to get it to work, although I am not sure I really changed anything very much. However, debugging PWAs is more complex than plain JavaScript. So most of my efforts were trial and error. And then it worked. Magic! 🧙‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even managed to get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/offline/&quot;&gt;offline page&lt;/a&gt; working for the PWA. Again, copied from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/offline&quot;&gt;Jeremy&#39;s offline page&lt;/a&gt;. What this page does, thanks to some nifty JavaScript, is check if there is a network connection. If there is it fetches the page from the server. If there isn&#39;t, it tries to fetch the page from the cache. If the page has not been cached, it displays a list of pages that have been cached and are therefore available for offline reading. Fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Dependencies</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dependencies/"/>
		<updated>2023-11-29T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/dependencies/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges, at least for me, in modern web development, is keeping track of dependencies. On the one hand they help you avoid reinventing the wheel. On the otherhand they can cause unexpected problems which are sometimes hard to diagnose. I like to keep them to a minimum, especially when I don&#39;t really understand how they do what they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I improved my GitHub action that builds my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/&quot;&gt;eleventy&lt;/a&gt; based website by removing my dependency on an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TartanLlama/actions-eleventy&quot;&gt;action from a GitHub user called TartanLlama&lt;/a&gt;. This action used a Docker file to build and generate the actual HTML pages for the website. The action has served me well for the last three years, but I did worry about what would happen if there was a bug and the user stopped maintaining this bit of code. It had stopped working once and it took me a couple of days to realise that I had to update my link to the action to a newer version. I didn&#39;t want to end up in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/dependency/&quot;&gt;this situation&lt;/a&gt;, should the user decide to call it a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did some Googling and found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockyourcode.com/how-to-deploy-eleventy-to-github-pages-with-github-actions/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/75599084&quot;&gt;this answer on Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/stackoverflow/&quot;&gt;Yes, I know I am trying to avoid Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;, but Google makes it very hard!). Between the two, I came up with this step in my GitHub action:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- name: Install dependencies &amp;amp; build
    run: |
        npm install --package-lock-only
        npm ci
        npm run build  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Neuromancer</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/"/>
		<updated>2023-11-12T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&#39;d heard a lot about this book. The author coined the term &amp;quot;cyberspace&amp;quot; and basically invented the cyberpunk genre. Back in the early 80s. So I finally decided I should read it and it made a very suitable follow up to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/androids-sheep/&quot;&gt;previous book&lt;/a&gt; I read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a fun read. I can see why it is so popular and how it would be a genre defining book. Very timely as well, with the rise of AI over the last year or two. Although that AI is nothing compared to what is described in this story. In fact the book is a suitable reminder that what we consider as AI right now, is nothing of the sort. It&#39;s certainly not intelligent, let alone self-aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the last quarter of the book in one evening. On putting it down and thinking about it for a while, there were more questions than answers. But the one thought which I couldn&#39;t get out of my mind, is that this was basically a blue print for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133093/&quot;&gt;The Matrix&lt;/a&gt;. Reading other people&#39;s thoughts on the web, I am clearly not the only one who came to this conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this book is part of a trilogoy. I guess they&#39;ll be my next two reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 03/11/2023. Finished 12/11/2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/neuromancer.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Stack Overflow</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/stackoverflow/"/>
		<updated>2023-11-09T07:00:01Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/stackoverflow/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I deleted all my accounts on stack overlfow and the other stack exchange sites. Why? I hadn&#39;t posted a question on the site in over 10 years as I no longer program very much and I find the answer increasingly less relevant when I am looking for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also come to understand  how its kudos system has a lot of negative side effects, turning what should be a friendly Q&amp;amp;A site into an agressively moderated online environment which is especially toxic to newbies who don&#39;t understand the rules. I had noticed myself that answers I gave over a decade ago were constantly re-edited and &amp;quot;improved&amp;quot;. Some questions I asked got completely rewritten or marked as duplicate even though I felt they weren&#39;t. This is the effect of members chasing kudos points in order to stay relevant in site&#39;s user rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also noticed that all search engines rely heavily, almost exclusively, on Stack Overflow to provide answers to programming questions asked to them. The problem which arises, is that the best answer from 10 years ago may no longer actually be the best answer. This is especially the case in web design where accepted best practice has moved on so much that an answer from 10 years ago is often simply no longer relevant. However, because the answer was edited 2 years ago the search engines still think it is up to date. This leads me to believe that the whole Q&amp;amp;A ecosystem created by Stack Overflow reeks of gaming the system. To the detriment of the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think the founders knew this. They &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.blog/2021/06/02/prosus-acquires-stack-overflow/&quot;&gt;sold the site for a cool $1.8 billion&lt;/a&gt; a couple of years ago, back in 2021. I think they realised they&#39;d pushed this as far as they could and in the long term further growth would be difficult. The new owners will for sure make a good profit over the coming years, it is after all &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; go to site for programming answers. But I doubt the next 15 years will match the success of the previous 15 years.  I can&#39;t see it maintaining its relevance, especially in this age of AI and tools like Copilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I for one, intend to avoid the stack exchange network as much as I can in future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Do Androids Dream Of Electric Sheep</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/androids-sheep/"/>
		<updated>2023-11-02T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/androids-sheep/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Philip K. Dick&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the book on which the film Blade Runner is based. I have always struggled to stay awake watching the film, as despite being interesting, it is very slow paced. The book on the other hand I finished in a couple of days. It&#39;s not gripping, but definitely interesting and raising some interesting questions about what is and isn&#39;t real. With the progress of AI in recent years, this is again a very current question. Well worth reading. And maybe I should watch the film again...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/androids-sheep.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Magic Mushroom</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/magic-mushroom/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-23T21:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/magic-mushroom/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A mushroom I came across whilst walking the dog in the woods on this overcast and damp morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/magic-mushroom.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Large red mushrooms with concentric rings of white dots and a black tip in the middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Techno-Optimist Manifesto</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/techno-optimist-manifesto/"/>
		<updated>2023-10-23T08:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/techno-optimist-manifesto/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Marc Andreessen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are my thoughts on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/the-techno-optimist-manifesto/&quot;&gt;The Techno-Optimist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; which made the web&#39;s techno news headlines recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s an ideology quite the opposite of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/communist-manifesto/&quot;&gt;Communist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, which I also read recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both promise us a much better life. They just get there by going in opposing directions. Neither of them seem to have much basis in actual reality in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole intro is a lie. We are not being told any of these things. We are told to be weary of thechnology, to treat it with respect. With great power comes great responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, except I didn&#39;t realise the technology flag had been lowered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm...  I agree with a lot of this. But he misses some major points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a problem of poverty, so we invent technology to create abundance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abundance for some, but at the moment this abundance is being wasted by the few rather than put to good use for the many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe this is why our descendents will live in the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, can we live in the stars before we use up all the resources on the planet. We haven&#39;t yet turned the corner on wasting resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Markets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markets prevent monopolies and cartels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No they don&#39;t. Plenty of monopolies in the world, also in the free capitalist world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe markets are an inherently individualistic way to achieve superior collective outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can believe that. Some people believe the earth is flat. It doesn&#39;t make it true. Where&#39;s the evidence for such a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe the ultimate moral defense of markets is that they divert people who otherwise would raise armies and start religions into peacefully productive pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if the spoils of the markets are fairly distributed. Not the case at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe markets are the way to generate societal wealth for everything else we want to pay for, including basic research, social welfare programs, and national defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we need social welfare programs if the markets actually worked?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would we need national defense, if we were living in the stars?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe a Universal Basic Income would turn people into zoo animals to be farmed by the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This I kind of agree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man was not meant to be farmed; man was meant to be useful, to be productive, to be proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmmm, useful to whom? Productive for what? We were not &lt;strong&gt;meant&lt;/strong&gt; to be anything, we simply &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being proud, without being arrogant, probably helps though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of valid points in this section. But since he is saying markets support the welfare state, then they must be taxed and regulated, otherwise how will this support work. Not quite the free markets he is intending. Or else we understand different things in &amp;quot;free markets&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Techno-Capital Machine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole section reads like a description of Iain M Banks&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/archive/tagged/iain-banks/&quot;&gt;Culture Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course that is science fiction and doesn&#39;t have to deal with the limited resources on planet earth. Nevermind the limits of physics and the physiology of our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t help feeling that &amp;quot;accelerationism&amp;quot; as he calls it, doesn&#39;t quite lead to what he thinks. Acceleration tends to stretch things. If you are not careful, the link between those at the front doing the pulling (the few super rich), and those at the back being pulled along (the poor), risks breaking. We could end up living in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elysium_(film)&quot;&gt;Elysium&lt;/a&gt; style &amp;quot;utopia&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligence is inate. But being smart needs high quality education. Limiting high quality education to the rich, as is increasingly happening now, means the compound effect of &amp;quot;intelligence * education&amp;quot; is being woefully exploited. Since intelligence is inate, it is equally spread through the population. But when only one segment of the population gets to use that intelligence, you are missing out on an awful lot of intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this chapter was like &amp;quot;what is this guy on&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as people form symbiotic relationships with machines into new cybernetic systems such as companies and networks;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course AI can and is beneficial, but only because it is powered by human intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Energy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fully agree with the point made on energy consumption in this section. We&#39;re not going to develop as a civilisation by using less energy. He also makes the point that using 1000x more energy does not need to be bad for the environment. I agree with that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then he says the current solution is nuclear fission. Whilst I don&#39;t disagree, I do think we need to urgently look beyond that technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He raises the prospect of nuclear fusion. Hopefully he is right on this. It can&#39;t come soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe technology is the solution to environmental degradation and crisis. A technologically advanced society improves the natural environment, a technologically stagnant society ruins it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are other ways in which an advanced society can ruin the environment which are not addressed by him (eg plastic pollution or habitat destruction), when it comes to energy, this is very true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Abundance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the post-scarcity society of Iain M Banks culture series, which I already mentioned previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this section makes sense, although I never like it when people are referred to as resources, even if they are &amp;quot;ultimate resources&amp;quot; in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure we could support 50 billion people on planet earth, but if the age of abundance leads to a lack of need for material goods, maybe it could. But we would still need to eat and drink! And I hope we would not end up, perhaps even voluntarily, as batteries powering the matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not Utopia, But Close Enough&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, although this section doesn&#39;t really say anything concrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Becoming Technological Supermen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing particularly outrageous here. All fairly obvious, but then couched in weird wording:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in the romance of technology, of industry. The eros of the train, the car, the electric light, the skyscraper. And the microchip, the neural network, the rocket, the split atom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in adventure. Undertaking the Hero’s Journey, rebelling against the status quo, mapping uncharted territory, conquering dragons, and bringing home the spoils for our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does he even realise that he is the status quo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in nature, but we also believe in overcoming nature. We are not primitives, cowering in fear of the lightning bolt. We are the apex predator; the lightning works for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in greatness. We admire the great technologists and industrialists who came before us, and we aspire to make them proud of us today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we believe in humanity – individually and collectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, but please: &amp;quot;apex predators&amp;quot;? If we&#39;re not careful we will saw off the branch we are sitting on as we climb up the tree of technological greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technological Values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in ambition, aggression, persistence, relentlessness – strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds more like greed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in merit and achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merit is great, it&#39;s unfortunate that we increasingly live in a world where merit doesn&#39;t really figure much. And no, money does not equal merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in embracing variance, in increasing interestingness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, it&#39;s unfortunate that our technological progress is making the whole world look identical. Identikit streets, shops and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And freedom of thought is great, but how come then people are obsessed with a few &amp;quot;great&amp;quot; educational institutions. Where&#39;s the variance in everyone thinking like a Havard student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in radical competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this even mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe extrinsic motivations – wealth, fame, revenge – are fine as far as they go. But we believe intrinsic motivations – the satisfaction of building something new, the camaraderie of being on a team, the achievement of becoming a better version of oneself – are more fulfilling and more lasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phew, he&#39;s not a complete capitalist then. Easy for someone to say who lucked into their first billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe technology is universalist. Technology doesn’t care about your ethnicity, race, religion, national origin, gender, sexuality, political views, height, weight, hair or lack thereof. Technology is built by a virtual United Nations of talent from all over the world. Anyone with a positive attitude and a cheap laptop can contribute. Technology is the ultimate open society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, technology is inclusive, if used correctly. Of course AI giving the job to the white guy rather than the black one is not fair or inclusive. It is simply following what it is trained on, subjective and biased decisions overwhelmingly made by white folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, there are still many people without even a cheap laptop. Probably over half the world&#39;s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in the Silicon Valley code of “pay it forward”, trust via aligned incentives, generosity of spirit to help one another learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the silicon valley I observe through the media. Maybe in reality it really is like this. But I doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe America and her allies should be strong and not weak. We believe national strength of liberal democracies flows from economic strength (financial power), cultural strength (soft power), and military strength (hard power). Economic, cultural, and military strength flow from technological strength. A technologically strong America is a force for good in a dangerous world. Technologically strong liberal democracies safeguard liberty and peace. Technologically weak liberal democracies lose to their autocratic rivals, making everyone worse off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fair point, if you consider the competing civilisations on this planet. I would rather we end up living in a democracy rather than an autocracy or dictatorship. But autocrats are currently making great use of technology to win their battles. Let&#39;s hope they don&#39;t win the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in fulfilling our potential, becoming fully human&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we are not currently &amp;quot;fully human&amp;quot;? If anything technology will make us less &amp;quot;human&amp;quot; with implants, replaced joints and who knows what enhancements in the future. I refer back to the Culture series...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Meaning of Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is true enough, but it hides behind this statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Techno-Optimism is a material philosophy, not a political philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this philosophy doesn&#39;t care about the politics, it then also doesn&#39;t have to care about the consequences of its theories. Which is quite handy, because everything has consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main theory being that technology makes things better, on averge. This is probably true, but not better for everyone and not equally so. There are always winners and losers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads to a big failing of this techno-optimist manifesto. It doesn&#39;t address the losers. It doesn&#39;t even address that there are losers. That is conveniently someone else&#39;s problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Enemy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts off so well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our enemies are not bad people – but rather bad ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then not so much goes downhill from there, but falls off a cliff. Pretty much any idea which doesn&#39;t fit into this guys pretty narrow world view is his enemy. Terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it takes on an almost missionary view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe we must help them find their way out of their self-imposed labyrinth of pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest enemy of progress are not all his enemies, but uniformity of thought, of philosophy, of ideas. If we all signed up to this guys manifesto, I am not sure things would turn out well for all of us. Certainly not in the short term, and there might not be a long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing particularly wrong or earth shattering in this concluding chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our civilization was built on a spirit of discovery, of exploration, of industrialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue, that above all else our civilisation was built on a spirit of cooperation. You don&#39;t get any of the above without cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What world are we building for our children and their children, and their children?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A world of fear, guilt, and resentment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or a world of ambition, abundance, and adventure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think anybody really argues against building a world of ambition, abundance and adventure. The issue is around the ideas that enable us to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patron Saints of Techno-Optimism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list of like minded persons, about half of whom are dead and one is fictional. They therefore cannot consent to being a patron saint of this manifesto. Just saying...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
