<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>robin.is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-04-09T09:18:27Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-09T09:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/happy-css-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th April is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today my site is naked.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Beebop Plovdiv</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-06T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lovely evening watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/hotclubdeplovdiv/&quot;&gt;Hot Club de Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beebopcafe.tv/&quot;&gt;Beebop Cafe in Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beebop-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/beebop-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Folkdance Ensemble Trakia</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/"/>
		<updated>2023-04-05T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/folkdance-trakia/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely evening, this time watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trakia-ensemble.org/en/&quot;&gt;folkdance ensemble Trakia&lt;/a&gt; perform at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://domborishristov.com/&quot;&gt;House of culture in Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fa-trakia-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Upgrading to Eleventy 2</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/eleventy-2-upgrade/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-30T09:12:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/eleventy-2-upgrade/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning I upgraded this site to be generated using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/blog/eleventy-v2/&quot;&gt;Eleventy 2.0.1&lt;/a&gt;. The process was dead simple thanks to this great &lt;a href=&quot;https://danabyerly.com/notes/upgrading-to-eleventy-2-0-0/&quot;&gt;post by Dana Byerly about the upgrade process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however encounter one strange problem with &lt;a href=&quot;https://lodash.com/&quot;&gt;lodash&lt;/a&gt;. After following the first three steps and then running the build command I received errors from npm about the missing &amp;quot;lodash&amp;quot; module. So I looked in my local node_modules and the only relevant folder there was &amp;quot;lodash.deburr&amp;quot;. I am not sure why, or even what the difference is between the two. Possibly this was something which worked in eleventy 1.0 but no longer in eleventy 2.0, no idea. So I ran &lt;code&gt;npm install lodash&lt;/code&gt; and then continued with step 4 and everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I need to see how to take advantage of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://11ty.rocks/posts/new-features-upgrade-considerations-eleventy-version-2/&quot;&gt;new features in Eleventy 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/usage/incremental/&quot;&gt;incremental builds&lt;/a&gt; during development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Follow the Money</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/follow-the-money/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-28T14:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/follow-the-money/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Paul Johnson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/follow-the-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an easy to follow whirlwind tour of where the UK government gets its money from and how it spends it. Full of facts and figures as well as some insightful commentary and significant critiscism of past taxation decisions across all parties. The biggest one being the lack of consistency, closely followed by lack of foresight and unwillngness to challenge current vested interests to improve the future of the country overall. Note that the latter is less about big business and lobbying and more about not wanting to upset the electorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely worth a read as it won&#39;t take you long. It took me a week. But what is missing is any real solution to these problems. Politicians have to win elections every few years so taking decisions which make some people poorer in the short term, but others better off in the long term is hard if you want to be re-elected. This conunmdrum is not solved by the book, which finishes with lots of good tips none of which will necessarily lead to an election victory in the current political climate. It finishes with the simple comment &amp;quot;must do better if we are to cope with the next crisis&amp;quot;. (Which, according to the book is going to be the climate crisis hitting at the same time as a really ageing population comes along.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there was one point which I didn&#39;t quite agree with. In the discussion on student loans the book compared the current loan system to the new one being brought in from September 2023. In the current system, the student loan increases at RPI + 3%, the threshold above which you have to repay at 9% is £27,500 and the loan is written off after 30 years. The estimate was that about 25% would repay their loan in full. In the new system the loan increases with RPI only, the threshold is £25,000 (and increases with RPI from 2025) and your loan is written off after 40 years. Paul&#39;s comparison of these two systems made the point that the old system was actually fairer because it penalises higher earners more. With the loan increasing above RPI higher earners are going to be repaying more overall in monetary terms than in the new system.This is because they will be repaying for longer as the amount owed increases quicker. Whereas for lower earners it doesn&#39;t matter because the amount owed is cleared after 30 years no matter how much was repaid. In the new system the amount owed does not increase so quickly, so higher earners will pay off their loan quicker and therefore pay less overall whereas lower earners will pay more because it is now 40 years before the loan is wiped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis is obviously correct, but there is one point not mentioned at this point in the book. And that is the relative parental wealth of higher vs lower earners. I found this strange because otherwise the book is generally covering wealth aspects well, often making the point that tax should be equitable and the wealthy should be taxed more, when this makes economic sense. I feel the analysis of the current system is wrong, because higher earners mostly come from wealthier backgrounds so it is more likely that their university fees will simply have been covered by their parents, putting them completely outside of the loan system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Matter</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/matter/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-19T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/matter/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 8th book in Iain M Banks&#39; series of Culture novels. It took me 2 and half months to slog through this book. Somehow I could not get into it eventhough the idea behind the Shellworlds is quite incredible. What I do like about the Culture novels is that even if the plot is not your thing, each book reveals a little more about the galaxy within which the Culture civilisation operates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story itself is OK in this book, perhaps not one of the better culture series storylines, but stil enjoyable. However it was not always captivating enough to keep me going. So I ended up putting it down for weeks at a time. I seemed to read it in spurts, including the last 100 pages on a Friday afternoon when work was slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best summary of this book I&#39;ve seen is &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/printSF/comments/wjou9/comment/c5dyx5d/&quot;&gt;Matter lacked substance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/matter.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Website carbon calculator</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/carbon-calculator/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-14T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/carbon-calculator/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/&quot;&gt;Website Carbon Calculator&lt;/a&gt; each view of this site&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.websitecarbon.com/website/robin-is/&quot;&gt;homepage produces 0.07g of CO2&lt;/a&gt;. It is therefore cleaner than 94% of web pages tested. Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing with other sites, it seems like the main component of this calculation is filesize. The homepage is about 300kB, depending on how many images happen to be on it. The biggest permanent component is the font file, which is 134kB and therefore contributes over a third of the CO2 prodcued by this homepage without actually contributing much to the function and usability of the site. Is the font file necessary? Perhaps I should switch back to using Arial? It&#39;s interesting how seemingly innocent design choices can have such an impact on the environment. For now it will stay as pretty much no one looks at this site.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Happy CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/happy-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-09T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/happy-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Todyay, 9th April, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today my site is naked.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CSS Naked Day</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/css-naked-day/"/>
		<updated>2023-03-03T09:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/css-naked-day/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 9th April is &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-naked-day.github.io/&quot;&gt;CSS Naked Day&lt;/a&gt;. On this day many bloggers remove all styling from their blog. The idea is to promote awarenes of web standards. A well designed site, following web standards, will work well without any styling. A follow-on aim is to raise awareness of accessibility, since the plain, unstyled website will feel more how someone with a screen reader and other assistive technology will experience the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In preparation for this, have updated my &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/robindotis/54786199b5d86f5085e5c55337d6e0d0&quot;&gt;theme picker&lt;/a&gt; to incldue a hard coded &amp;quot;Naked&amp;quot; CSS theme. If desired, this theme will be forced on CSS Naked Day, with no alternative for the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Cat by log fire</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cat-by-fire/"/>
		<updated>2023-02-24T21:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cat-by-fire/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the neighbour&#39;s cat sitting by the log fire!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/cat-by-log-fire.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cat sitting on a router in front of a TV displaying a log fire on the screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eagle eyed will notice she is actually keeping warm on the router!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
