<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin . is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-08-16T19:12:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>The work archives</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/work-archives/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-16T19:12:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/work-archives/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I did some physical archiving, as opposed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/archiving/&quot;&gt;virtual archiving&lt;/a&gt; I do here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues of mine had spent the last few weeks disappearing into our archives, to clear them out ahead of our move to a new building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it turns out most of them can be binned, so I spent Wednesday afternoon helping them finish off the process of sorting them into paper for recycling, CDs, plastic for the main rubbish and piles and piles of folders presumably for shipping into the past for reuse in a time when they were useful. All our archives have now been digital for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was really a case of chucking stuff out rather than archiving, but it felt good and I felt productive once I saw the boxes we filled! 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also interesting to see colleagues&#39; names on the project folders from 15 years ago. I now feel slightly less frustrated when I have to ask them for the third time how to do things. I&#39;ve only been in the unit 4 years!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Inaccessible Code</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inaccessible-code/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-16T12:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inaccessible-code/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like this summary from Eric of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ericwbailey.website/published/the-five-types-of-people-who-produce-inaccessible-code/&quot;&gt;types of people who create inaccessible code&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code, but do not realize they are doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code and realize they are doing so, but do not know how to fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code, and do not care about fixing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code that they think is accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code that our industry thinks is accessible, but experientially is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Surface Detail</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/surface-detail/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-27T20:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/surface-detail/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got through this book in 10 days whilst on holiday. Reading it over such a short time frame helped me to keep the storyline fresh in mind. Maybe because of this, I feel it is certainly one of the better Culture series books. Somewhat unusually it ties up all the loose ends and leaves nothing unexplained. Maybe because by now readers are aware of the all encompassing power of the Culture civilisation and the trickery this enables them engage in. And yet it is not necessarily the most powerful civilisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/surface-detail.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Fotinovo</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fotinovo/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-25T21:30:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fotinovo/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/&quot;&gt;short hike yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, we decided to follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hikes-and-walks.com/hike/bulgaria/fotinski-waterfalls&quot;&gt;Waterfall trail in Fotinovo&lt;/a&gt;, about 100 minutes drive from Plovdiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 6km hike to the waterfalls and back, as well as a steep descent to actually see the waterfalls. Most of the info I could find about the trail indicated this was an easy hike. The descent to the waterfalls and subsequent climb back up are anything but. It didn&#39;t help that we did the hike on the hottest day of the year so far. It was 33°C in Fotinovo and 40°C in Plovdiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The waterfalls were interesting and worth the effort, but not exceptionally so. Maybe they are more imposing in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The waterfalls seen from the bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The bridge at the bottom to get to the waterfalls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Another view of the waterfalls from the bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The river flowing into the waterfalls, which the trail follows to get to the falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The edge of the village where the trail starts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A workshop where we got some directions at the start of the trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The trail leading past some meadows towards the waterfalls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Byala Cherkva</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-24T21:30:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We spent an hour hiking around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/3Dz1p9kAH55Z9jAr9&quot;&gt;Byala Cherkva&lt;/a&gt; area inn order to escape the 39°C heat in Plovdiv. It&#39;s not really a starting point for any trails, so we just set off down the road and turned round 45 minutes later. It was a nice walk, still hot despite being half way up the Rodopi mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/byala-cherkva-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Brown butterfly with orange trim containing black dots nestling on a yellow flower with the green foliage blurred in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Kapana</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/kapana/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-23T17:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/kapana/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://visitkapana.bg/en/about-the-district/&quot;&gt;Kapana&lt;/a&gt; (Капана), Bulgarian for trap, is an area of central Plovdiv with small streets.  Traditional where handicrafts people setup their workshops, it was then a bit of an artists area. For as long as I have known Plovdiv (around 20 years) it was always a bit of a rundown and underused area, from a tourist perspective. It has been completely redone in the last couple of years and turned into a great street cafe area. It&#39;s especially busy in the evenings and judging by the languages I heard, popular with the tourists. Well worth a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Kapana in the late evening&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Kapana in the late evening&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great vegan meal in a small cafe called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veggic.bg/&quot;&gt;VEGGIC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;VEGGIC restaurant serving great vegan food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course all progress has its downsides. This sort of gentrification also means the people who used to run art ateliers and crafts workshops here can no longer afford to do so. Thankfully though there are, in my opinion, still enough areas of central Plovdiv that need restoring that those traders will find somewhere nearby to set up shop. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Oft Robin</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/oft-robin/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-16T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/oft-robin/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely evening &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/&quot;&gt;watching jazz again&lt;/a&gt;, this time listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://viktorbenev.com/oft-robin.html&quot;&gt;Oft Robin&lt;/a&gt; in &amp;quot;Room 1&amp;quot; of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bnr.bg/plovdiv/&quot;&gt;Radio Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt; building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 18 people watching, possibly we were the only ones not included in &amp;quot;Family and Friends&amp;quot; 🙂. The group is great so it&#39;s surprising there weren&#39;t more people in the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/oft-robin-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/oft-robin-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Freakonomics</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/freakonomics/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-09T09:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/freakonomics/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Steven D. Levitt and Stephen J Dubner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A straightforward read about what happens when you use the data available to answer interesting questions. The key being that you need to know to ask these interesting questions in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the data driven world we now live in it is on the one hand now not that exceptional, 20 years after it&#39;s first publication. On the other hand it underlines the need to ask interesting questions if we are going to make good use of all this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the added on chapters included the question &amp;quot;Why do people vote when no single vote ever really matters&amp;quot;. Whilst the point being is valid, in reality every vote counts. As the recent, potentially manipulated by targeted advertising, vote on Brexit showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/freakonomics.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Arctic Monkeys</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/arctic-monkeys/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-05T07:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/arctic-monkeys/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not one, but two concerts in a week for us. We just got back from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/rock-werchter-2023/&quot;&gt;Rock Werchter on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday 4th July and we were back in front of a stage. This time watching the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arcticmonkeys.com/&quot;&gt;Arctic Monkeys&lt;/a&gt; at the more conveniently located Luxexpo in Luxembourg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got there at 8.45pm, just in time to watch the band take the stage. Not really knowing too much of their music, I found it interesting and well worth attending. The stage setup and the music was a bit of throwback to the &#39;50s which made the whole evening very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/arctic-monkeys-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Arctic Monkeys on stage at the Luxexpo.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/arctic-monkeys-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Arctic Monkeys on stage in the fading light with the spotlights on full power pointing at the crowd.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/arctic-monkeys-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Arctic Monkeys on stage.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Rock Werchter 2023</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/rock-werchter-2023/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-01T09:20:30Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/rock-werchter-2023/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having enjoyed last year&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/rock-werchter-2022/&quot;&gt;day at Rock Werchter&lt;/a&gt; so much, we got to tickets to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://redhotchilipeppers.com/&quot;&gt;Red Hot Chili Peppers&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rockwerchter.be/en/&quot;&gt;Rock Werchter 2023&lt;/a&gt; this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Black Keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was a work day, we only got there around 6.30pm and first up were the Black Keys. They were not really our thing, but it was a good start to the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/black-keys.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The Black Keys playing on the Main stage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst waiting for Liam Gallagher to appear on the main stage, we walked around a little and caught the last few minutes of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehuofficial.com/music&quot;&gt;The Hu&lt;/a&gt; on the Klub C stage. They are a monogolian rock / techno / group whom I did not know before and they were great. I will have to find another show of theirs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/the-hu.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The Hu playing on the Klub C stage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we ambled over to the Slope where we watched Canadian group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.puptheband.com/&quot;&gt;Pup&lt;/a&gt; for about 15 minutes, who were also good fun whith fantastic music. Interestingly the Slope had been turned around so it faced the stage, rather than the stage being underneath it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/pup.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Pup playing on the Slope stage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Liam Gallagher&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned to the main stage to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liamgallagher.com/home/&quot;&gt;Liam Gallagher&lt;/a&gt; play, but we were not impressed. Nor were the crowd I don&#39;t think. Oasis were great in their day and their songs are still fantastic. But on stage, Liam was very poor and lifeless. I realise that is his thing, but times have changed and I think crowds expect more of a show. It didn&#39;t help that he completely failed to build up a connection with the crowd - his arrogant appearance and inuendos not really making an impact. You&#39;re not in Manchester, Liam, it&#39;s Rock Werchter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/liam-gallagher.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Liam Gallagher on the main stage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Red Hot Chili Peppers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hung around near the front of the Main stage for an hour, until Red Hot Chili Peppers were on at 23:30. We were thinking of getting into the enclosure right in front of the stage, but decided not to. So we watched them from the &amp;quot;second row&amp;quot; as it were. They were great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rhcp-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Flea and John Frusciante performing on the Main stage.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rhcp-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Anthony Kiedes singing on the Main stage.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rhcp-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Chad Smith on the drums for Red Hot Chili Peppers.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rhcp-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Two girls on the shoulders of their friends in front of the main stage watching Red Hot Chili Peppers.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/rhcp-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The final song of the Red Hot Chili Peppers at Rock Werchter 2023.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Night Rock Werchter, again!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
