<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2024-02-19T18:00:33Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Burning Chrome</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/burning-chrome/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-19T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/burning-chrome/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collection of short stories by William Gibson. Some based around the Neuromancer world, others unrealted. I found some quite abstract and unclear, making it  hard to understand the story. Others were great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great read - they made a film of this one, starring Keanu Reeves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gernsback Continuum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An odd one. Somewhat tricky to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fragments of a Hologram rose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very short story, again rather abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Belonging Kid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About aliens mingling amongst humans on earth. An interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hinterlands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A really interesting story about a sort of tunnel to another galaxy or universe. One of my favourites in this collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Red Star, Winter Orbit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Rose Hotel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Winter Market&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dogfight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Burning Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 13/02/2024. Finished 19/02/2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/burning-chrome.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Madrid</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/madrid/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-19T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/madrid/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A relaxing few days in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14/02&lt;br /&gt;
We arrived at the central station around 15:30 and got to our hotel around 18:00 after catching a local train to the airport terminal 4 and then a local bus for three stops to Barajas where our hotel was, Hotel Clement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15/02&lt;br /&gt;
TBD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16/02&lt;br /&gt;
TBD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17/02&lt;br /&gt;
Return to Luxembourg.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Barcelona</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/barcelona/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-14T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/barcelona/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A relaxing few days in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/02&lt;br /&gt;
We arrived around 3pm at our appartment. Then walked around town for a few hours, before having dinner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11/02&lt;br /&gt;
A day strolling around town. Visited Joan Miro park, and the circular shopping arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12/02&lt;br /&gt;
Visited the hospital at Sant Pau.&lt;br /&gt;
Piano concert at the Palau of mnusic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13/02&lt;br /&gt;
Went to the funicular for Tibidabo, but it was out of order, so we spent the rest of the day walking arounf the area, having a lovely lunch at la tegliatlle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14/02&lt;br /&gt;
Got high speed train to Madrid&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Mona Lisa Overdrive</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/mona-lisa-overdrive/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-13T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/mona-lisa-overdrive/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of his trilogy, that starts with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer.md&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt; and continues with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero.md&quot;&gt;Count Zero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 07/02/2024. Finished 13/02/2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/mona-lisa-overdrive.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Weekend in London</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/london-weekend/"/>
		<updated>2024-01-29T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/london-weekend/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lovely short weekend in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday we walked around the Bloomsbury area, having a great late lunch in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gigsfishandchips.com/&quot;&gt;Gigs&lt;/a&gt; near Goodge Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late afternoon, we walked around the last day of the winter lights exhibition at Canary Wharf, before watching Les Miserables at the Sondheim Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Looking up at the HSBC building from within the winter lights exhibition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow lights moving a curved and looped line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Line drawn figures projected on a large screen provided by a building in construction with a neutron exhibit in the foreground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Small lights hanging from ropes arranged in a square viewed from outside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Now seen from within, giving the impression of being submerged&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Interval scene of Les Miserables with lady dressed in white waving large red revolutionary flag in front clouds lit up by sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Boliartsi</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/boliartsi/"/>
		<updated>2024-01-02T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/boliartsi/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The original pale green and yellow vertically striped walls in Boliartsi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/boliartsi.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Can&#39;t we just print more money</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-31T23:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Rupal Patel and Jack Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A book on introductory economics written by employees of the The Bank of England. Very easy to read and generally easy to follow. Understanding some of the theory without some background knowledge of economics might be difficult though. The book could have paid more attention to explaining some of the terminology and concepts. Still it is a good book to get a better understanding of some of the everyday questions on economics you might have. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What causes recessions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is inflation and is it good or bad?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are banks useful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should governments be in debt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the book&#39;s title: Can&#39;t we just print more money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some criticism is due because it tends to support the status quo, along the lines of &amp;quot;it is what it is&amp;quot;. It is honest enough to stress that economics is not a real science and very much hit and miss. It also finishes with a &amp;quot;call to arms&amp;quot;, trying to get more people interested in economics in order to shake up the status quo. More discussions on some of the social consequences of the choices available to governments, banks and economists would have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the different types of taxes that can be raised and from whom. Taxing the very rich or companies has very different consequences to taxing the poor. If the aim is to keep money in the system, then there needs to be a way to limit the very rich from taking it out of the system and put it in offshore bank accounts for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the US can run much larger debt ratio than other countries, because of its political and military importance. Similarly, Japan has the highest debt ratio in the world, but this is not a problem because much of it is held by its citizens and generally the world trusts Japan to repay its debt. So again, like taxes, not all debt is equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book does hint at these sorts of questions in the conclusion and it is intended as an introduction, not a study. It also mentions that most of the public does not understand the consequences of the economic policies they are voting for. Addressing things like taxation and debt in more detail, but still in plain language, might have been useful in achieving the goals of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Count Zero</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-23T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count Zero is the follow on book to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;, which I read last month. It took me a little longer to finish, so I think I missed some of the detail. It was an interesting read, possibly more so even than Neuromancer, although not as ground breaking. I think I will have to re-read this one in a shorter time frame to make more sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 13/11/2023. Finished 22/12/2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/count-zero.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Angie&#39;s Christmas Tale</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-20T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, walking Angie in one of the locations we rarely go to, Angie disappeared. I was walking ahead as usual, she was dilly dallying at the back. When I retraced my steps to go and find her, she was gone. After about half an hour of whistling and shouting I started to get quite worried. I went back to the car to see if she was there, then I called my wife to come back from work to help find her. I also called a nearby neighbour who I know from walking our dogs. She came and helped look with her dog, Tashi. But all to no good. She phoned her bedsitter to check if Angie had returned to our house. No luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neighbour went back to the village, and opened the gate to our garden so Angie could go in, if she returned. At that time my wife had returned home as well and between them half the village was now looking for Angie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I went back to my car and drove down the hill to the houses below where we were walking. This was about 90 minutes after she went missing. Walking around there, a lady came out of one of the houses, asking if I was looking for a dog. I said yes, and she mentioned that another lady, a teacher, had found a dog and put her in her van and gone to work at the school. The teacher had given the lady her phone number. So I got in touch with the teacher and started heading to the school she worked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out the teacher had already posted a message on Facebook which our direct neighbour had already seen, recognised Angie, contacted the teacher separately and was heading to the school with my wife. I followed along and we were reunited with Angie about two and half hours after she went missing. They&#39;d even cleaned her! I guess dirty dogs are not allowed in schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very nice to see how quickly things can come together when everyone helps - and how social media can actually be put to good use as well from time to time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is my Christmas Tale for 2023. 🎅🎄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angies-christmas-tale.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angie waiting to be picked up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Progressive Web App</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-09T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to make my website installable, so it can be added to a device as an installed application. The way to do this is to add some javascript to the site so that it is a Progressive Web App (PWA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a PWA, a website needs only one thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.dev/learn/pwa/service-workers/&quot;&gt;service worker&lt;/a&gt;. Adding one is fairly straightforward, once you know how. It does require a good understanding of asynchronous JavaScript, something which I struggle with. The alternative is just to copy someone else&#39;s service worker code and adapt if needed. I chose the alternative. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I copied the one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt;. It took me a while to get it to work, although I am not sure I really changed anything very much. However, debugging PWAs is more complex than plain JavaScript. So most of my efforts were trial and error. And then it worked. Magic! 🧙‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even managed to get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/offline/&quot;&gt;offline page&lt;/a&gt; working for the PWA. Again, copied from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/offline&quot;&gt;Jeremy&#39;s offline page&lt;/a&gt;. What this page does, thanks to some nifty JavaScript, is check if there is a network connection. If there is it fetches the page from the server. If there isn&#39;t, it tries to fetch the page from the cache. If the page has not been cached, it displays a list of pages that have been cached and are therefore available for offline reading. Fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
