<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2024-02-19T18:00:33Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Burning Chrome</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/burning-chrome/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-19T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/burning-chrome/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collection of short stories by William Gibson. Some based around the Neuromancer world, others unrealted. I found some quite abstract and unclear, making it  hard to understand the story. Others were great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great read - they made a film of this one, starring Keanu Reeves. It&#39;s about a person who can securely store other&#39;s private data in his brain so that only they can access it. This one is based in the same universe as the Neuromancer triology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Gernsback Continuum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An odd one. Somewhat tricky to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fragments of a Hologram rose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very short story, again rather abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Belonging Kid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About aliens mingling amongst humans on earth. An interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hinterlands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A really interesting story about a sort of tunnel to another galaxy or universe. One of my favourites in this collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Red Star, Winter Orbit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fascinating story about a Russian space station inhabited by civilians called Kosmograd. One of them, the first person to walk on Mars, has been in space for 20 years and can&#39;t return. Then Russia decides to pull the plug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Rose Hotel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the Neuromancer cyberpunk world, dealing with gloabl coorporations figthing for scientists at the very &amp;quot;edge&amp;quot; of research into bio technology. Two spies help these scientists in dealing with these corporations. It deals with the exact same topic of the Neuromancer trilogoy and was released at the same time. It seems like he was testing the water with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Winter Market&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story deals with making recordings of people&#39;s thoughts and then selling them as entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dogfight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a loner with a criminal past wanting to make his next million by beating the top dog at a computer game that is played through being jacked into a headset type thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Burning Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story that started it all, where the term &amp;quot;cyperspace&amp;quot; was first coined. It only uses the term once, rght in the second sentence of the first paragraph. It does so almost in passing and it is otherwise unremarkable in the context of the story. But there it is: &amp;quot;cyberspace&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story itself is an interesting one, setting the scene for Neuromancer and it&#39;s two follow up stories. It deals with two guys essentially doing a bank heist. One to impress a girl, the other to get the money. The clue is that term coined by William Gibson. The heist happens in cyberspace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 13/02/2024. Finished 19/02/2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/burning-chrome.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Madrid</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/madrid/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-18T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/madrid/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a nice few days in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/barcelona/&quot;&gt;Barcelona&lt;/a&gt;, we took a high speed iryo train to Madrid. Travelling at up to 300km/h we covered the over 600km journey in about two hours and 45 minutes, including a brief stop in Zaragoza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the central station, Puerta de Atocha, around 15:30. We then took a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.renfe.com/es/es/cercanias&quot;&gt;Cercanias&lt;/a&gt; local train, which was included in our ticket from Barcelona, to get to the airport terminal T4 and then took the 827 bus to Barajas. We walked the remaining five minutes to our hotel,  Hotel Clement, arriving around 18:00.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having checked in, we went out to get some food, settling on a Nepalese place, as everything else was booked out due to it being valentines day. The food was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we headed into town with a friend who gave us a good walking tour around Madrid. We started off at Place d&#39;Espanya with a statue of Cervantes in the middle and surrounded by rather grandiose and imposing buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we headed up the Gran Via to Plaza del Callao and on to Puerta del Sol. This is the starting point in Madrid for all distances to other towns, kilometre zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We carried on to Plaza Mayor. The name is similar to Brussels&#39; Grande Place, but the looks are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed onto Mercado de San Miguel...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...before reaching the Royal Palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are statues of the previous spanish kings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-8.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was time for a late lunch, before continuing in the direction of the Prado and a quick look at Place de Colon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/madrid-9.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we reached the Prado, which has free entry after 6pm. You need more than the two hours this affords you to cover the whole museum. But I looked at some of the Cervantes paintings, as well as the famous Dos de Mayo and Tres de Mayo paintings. I also spotted the painting of a lady squirting breast milk into a priest&#39;s mouth, one which I had noticed over 20 years ago on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2001/spain/&quot;&gt;last visit to Madrid&lt;/a&gt;. But did not spot the painting by Bosch that I noted at the time. Maybe it was on loan to somewhere else. Or maybe it was not actually by Bosch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day I was ill so I didn&#39;t do a lot, whilst the other went out. The next morning we flew back to Luxembourg. Not without a minor panic though. For whatever reason my younger daughter&#39;s wallet, including ID card, was with my older daughter. Only problem was that we were flying from different terminals at opposite ends of the airport! We realised this at check-in. Thankfully a) the airport has an efficient transfer bus between the two terminals every five minutes and b) my older daughter&#39;s flight was an hour later. On the other hand she had already gone through security. Still she found her way out of the Terminal, to the transfer bus, brought us the wallet and saved the day. No one missed their flight! 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing in Spain seem to be that you are charged extra (a three Euro supplement per person) to take the metro to the airport. It means for a family of four this 12 Euros on top of the actual metro ticket. So you are easily looking at 20 Euro. An Uber is not much more to some locations from the airport. This makes no sense, I thought policy was to encourage taking public transport. This seems to discourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Barcelona</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/barcelona/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-14T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/barcelona/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having enjoyed our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2022/barcelona/&quot;&gt;last visit to Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; a couple of years ago, we decided to visit again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived around 3pm at our appartment, a few  blocks north of the Sagrada Familia near the restored Sant Pau hospital. The appartment was nice, and we even had a view, just, of the Sagrada Familia from our Balcony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having checked in, we walked around town for a few hours, before having dinner and returning to the appartment. They haven&#39;t yet completed the Sagrada Familia, but I like to think they progressed since our last visit, given all the scaffolding around parts of the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we strolled around town a little more.  We visited the Joan Miro park...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...followed by the Barcelona Arena shopping centre which has a viewing platform all the way around its roof. From there we got a good view of the Place d&#39;Espanya and the National Palace on the Montjiuc hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the third day we visited the wonderfully restored hospital at Sant Pau, which is now a museum. They don&#39;t build hospitals like that anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the day watching a piano concert by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.khatiabuniatishvili.com/&quot;&gt;Khatia Buniatishvili&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palaumusica.cat/en/khatia-buniatishvili-piano_1004121&quot;&gt;Palau de la Musica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our final full day we intended to visit Tibidabo castle, so headed for the funicular. Unforuntately it was out of order, so we spent the rest of the day ambling around the area, having a lovely lunch at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latagliatella.es/&quot;&gt;La Tegliatlla&lt;/a&gt; restaurant.  Then we enjoyed some lovely views of the city from Park del Turo del Putxet a bit further along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-8.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/barcelona-9.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/madrid/&quot;&gt;we were off to Madrid&lt;/a&gt; on a high speed train.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Mona Lisa Overdrive</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/mona-lisa-overdrive/"/>
		<updated>2024-02-13T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/mona-lisa-overdrive/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final part of his trilogy, that starts with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt; and continues with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/&quot;&gt;Count Zero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finishing it in under a week made it easier to follow and keep track of what was going on. A very enjoyable read with an interesting ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly like the way this trilogoy has done quite well at predicting the future. Not in terms of the cyberpunk background, but in the way it has made information and not technology itself the centre of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 07/02/2024. Finished 13/02/2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/mona-lisa-overdrive.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Weekend in London</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/london-weekend/"/>
		<updated>2024-01-29T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/london-weekend/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lovely short weekend in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday we walked around the Bloomsbury area, having a great late lunch in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gigsfishandchips.com/&quot;&gt;Gigs&lt;/a&gt; near Goodge Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late afternoon, we walked around the last day of the winter lights exhibition at Canary Wharf, before watching Les Miserables at the Sondheim Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Looking up at the HSBC building from within the winter lights exhibition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Yellow lights moving a curved and looped line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Line drawn figures projected on a large screen provided by a building in construction with a neutron exhibit in the foreground&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Small lights hanging from ropes arranged in a square viewed from outside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Now seen from within, giving the impression of being submerged&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/london-weekend-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Interval scene of Les Miserables with lady dressed in white waving large red revolutionary flag in front clouds lit up by sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Boliartsi</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/boliartsi/"/>
		<updated>2024-01-02T19:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2024/boliartsi/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The original pale green and yellow vertically striped walls in Boliartsi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2024/boliartsi.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Can&#39;t we just print more money</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-31T23:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Rupal Patel and Jack Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A book on introductory economics written by employees of the The Bank of England. Very easy to read and generally easy to follow. Understanding some of the theory without some background knowledge of economics might be difficult though. The book could have paid more attention to explaining some of the terminology and concepts. Still it is a good book to get a better understanding of some of the everyday questions on economics you might have. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What causes recessions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is inflation and is it good or bad?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are banks useful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should governments be in debt?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the book&#39;s title: Can&#39;t we just print more money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some criticism is due because it tends to support the status quo, along the lines of &amp;quot;it is what it is&amp;quot;. It is honest enough to stress that economics is not a real science and very much hit and miss. It also finishes with a &amp;quot;call to arms&amp;quot;, trying to get more people interested in economics in order to shake up the status quo. More discussions on some of the social consequences of the choices available to governments, banks and economists would have been useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the different types of taxes that can be raised and from whom. Taxing the very rich or companies has very different consequences to taxing the poor. If the aim is to keep money in the system, then there needs to be a way to limit the very rich from taking it out of the system and put it in offshore bank accounts for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, the US can run much larger debt ratio than other countries, because of its political and military importance. Similarly, Japan has the highest debt ratio in the world, but this is not a problem because much of it is held by its citizens and generally the world trusts Japan to repay its debt. So again, like taxes, not all debt is equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book does hint at these sorts of questions in the conclusion and it is intended as an introduction, not a study. It also mentions that most of the public does not understand the consequences of the economic policies they are voting for. Addressing things like taxation and debt in more detail, but still in plain language, might have been useful in achieving the goals of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/cant-we-just-print-more-money.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Count Zero</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-23T08:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/count-zero/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by William Gibson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Count Zero is the follow on book to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/neuromancer/&quot;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;, which I read last month. It took me a little longer to finish, so I think I missed some of the detail. It was an interesting read, possibly more so even than Neuromancer, although not as ground breaking. I think I will have to re-read this one in a shorter time frame to make more sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started 13/11/2023. Finished 22/12/2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/count-zero.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Angie&#39;s Christmas Tale</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-20T13:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/angies-christmas-tale/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, walking Angie in one of the locations we rarely go to, Angie disappeared. I was walking ahead as usual, she was dilly dallying at the back. When I retraced my steps to go and find her, she was gone. After about half an hour of whistling and shouting I started to get quite worried. I went back to the car to see if she was there, then I called my wife to come back from work to help find her. I also called a nearby neighbour who I know from walking our dogs. She came and helped look with her dog, Tashi. But all to no good. She phoned her bedsitter to check if Angie had returned to our house. No luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neighbour went back to the village, and opened the gate to our garden so Angie could go in, if she returned. At that time my wife had returned home as well and between them half the village was now looking for Angie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I went back to my car and drove down the hill to the houses below where we were walking. This was about 90 minutes after she went missing. Walking around there, a lady came out of one of the houses, asking if I was looking for a dog. I said yes, and she mentioned that another lady, a teacher, had found a dog and put her in her van and gone to work at the school. The teacher had given the lady her phone number. So I got in touch with the teacher and started heading to the school she worked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out the teacher had already posted a message on Facebook which our direct neighbour had already seen, recognised Angie, contacted the teacher separately and was heading to the school with my wife. I followed along and we were reunited with Angie about two and half hours after she went missing. They&#39;d even cleaned her! I guess dirty dogs are not allowed in schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very nice to see how quickly things can come together when everyone helps - and how social media can actually be put to good use as well from time to time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is my Christmas Tale for 2023. 🎅🎄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/angies-christmas-tale.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Angie waiting to be picked up&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Progressive Web App</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/"/>
		<updated>2023-12-09T08:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/installable/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to make my website installable, so it can be added to a device as an installed application. The way to do this is to add some javascript to the site so that it is a Progressive Web App (PWA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a PWA, a website needs only one thing: a &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.dev/learn/pwa/service-workers/&quot;&gt;service worker&lt;/a&gt;. Adding one is fairly straightforward, once you know how. It does require a good understanding of asynchronous JavaScript, something which I struggle with. The alternative is just to copy someone else&#39;s service worker code and adapt if needed. I chose the alternative. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I copied the one from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt;. It took me a while to get it to work, although I am not sure I really changed anything very much. However, debugging PWAs is more complex than plain JavaScript. So most of my efforts were trial and error. And then it worked. Magic! 🧙‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even managed to get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/offline/&quot;&gt;offline page&lt;/a&gt; working for the PWA. Again, copied from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/offline&quot;&gt;Jeremy&#39;s offline page&lt;/a&gt;. What this page does, thanks to some nifty JavaScript, is check if there is a network connection. If there is it fetches the page from the server. If there isn&#39;t, it tries to fetch the page from the cache. If the page has not been cached, it displays a list of pages that have been cached and are therefore available for offline reading. Fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
