<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/feed/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Robin . is</title>
	<subtitle>writing, travelling, seeing, coding and walking the 🐕‍🦺</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/feed/index.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.robin.is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
	<updated>2023-08-24T07:47:29Z</updated>
	<id>https://www.robin.is/</id>
	<author>
		<name>robindotis</name>
		<email>admin@robin.is</email>
	</author>
	
	
	<entry>
		<title>Around Bofferdange</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/around-bofferange/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-24T07:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/around-bofferange/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some photos from my local area in Bofferdange, Luxembourg. It&#39;s very pretty when it&#39;s sunny. Right now it&#39;s pouring down! 😒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow over a valley, in front and through the clouds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Green valley with wooded hills in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Wheat kernel in front of the morning sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/boffer-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Stacks of harvested wheat waiting in the field to be collected in the morning sun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Hydrogen Sonata</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/hyrdogen-sonata/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-22T18:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/hyrdogen-sonata/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His final Culture Series novel before his death marks a very fitting end to the series. It covers the notion of Subliming, where by advanced galactic civilisations voluntarily dissapear into the &amp;quot;Ether&amp;quot; as they feel their time in the &amp;quot;Real&amp;quot; is finished. As such it has some qualities of death itself. I don&#39;t think Banks knew he had cancer when writing this book. Judging by the interview in the back of the book he was planning on writing more Culture novels. Sadly that will not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions this book asks is do you tell your good friend and distant relative that the whole basis and meaning of their life was a lie just before they die. You know they have this suspicion, but still they believe they lie. Do you tell them or do you let them go to the other side believing a lie? Perhaps it doesn&#39;t matter even if you tell them. They like the lie too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/hydrogen-sonata.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Manifesto of the Communist Party</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/communist-manifesto/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-21T07:45:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/communist-manifesto/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/communist-manifesto.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussing some of Iain M Banks&#39; socialist theories in his Culture novels, a friend of mine commented: &amp;quot;but that&#39;s from Karl Marx&#39;s Communist Manifesto&amp;quot;. I figured it might be good to read the manifesto, so I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1848/communist-manifesto/index.htm&quot;&gt;downloaded and printed it out from the internet&lt;/a&gt;. At around 50 pages it&#39;s quite short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my random thoughts on the manifesto. &lt;strong&gt;They are probably wrong&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I thought there were a lot valid points criticising capitalism in this chapter. However I can&#39;t help feeling that the end state of the Communist Manifesto is some sort Utopia in permanent stasis. But this is not realistic, change is the basis of life and trying to oppose the forces of change always fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked this paragraph as it still seems relevant today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is enough to mention the commercial crises that by their periodical return put the existence of the entire bourgeois society on its trial, each time more threateningly. In these crises, a great part not only of the existing products, but also of the previously created productive forces, are periodically destroyed. In these crises, there breaks out an epidemic that, in all earlier epochs, would have seemed an absurdity — the epidemic of over-production&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t like the idea of the proletariat overthrowing the bourgoisie being the legitimate end game and that only the proletariat class seem to have some god given right to survive. The proletatriat will need leaders, which will attract the power hungry and off we go again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as, therefore, at an earlier period, a section of the nobility went over to the bourgeoisie, so now a portion of the bourgeoisie goes over to the proletariat, and in particular, a portion of the bourgeois ideologists, who have raised themselves to the level of comprehending theoretically the historical movement as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the classes that stand face to face with the bourgeoisie today, the proletariat alone is a really revolutionary class. The other classes decay and finally disappear in the face of Modern Industry; the proletariat is its special and essential product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will just &amp;quot;rinse-repeat&amp;quot;. Round and round we go. Why should the proletariat be different to the peasants in previous centuries? The premise appears to be that technological progress is the difference between now and then. But I don&#39;t buy that. Unless of course thechnology is used to maintain the whole thing by force, as happened in eastern Europe - poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Communists, therefore, are on the one hand, practically, the most advanced and resolute section of the working-class parties of every country, that section which pushes forward all others; on the other hand, theoretically, they have over the great mass of the proletariat the advantage of clearly understanding the line of march, the conditions, and the ultimate general results of the proletarian movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the &amp;quot;Communists&amp;quot; will be the better amongst equals, because what, they are better educated? But they are better educated because they come from the upper classes. As invariably always happens, the Communists will end up ruling over the proletariat, not with them...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, there are some very good and valid criticism of capitalism, but only poor solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National differences and antagonism between peoples are daily more and more vanishing, owing to the development of the bourgeoisie, to freedom of commerce, to the world market, to uniformity in the mode of production and in the conditions of life corresponding thereto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supremacy of the proletariat will cause them to vanish still faster. United action, of the leading civilised countries at least, is one of the first conditions for the emancipation of the proletariat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In proportion as the exploitation of one individual by another will also be put an end to, the exploitation of one nation by another will also be put an end to. In proportion as the antagonism between classes within the nation vanishes, the hostility of one nation to another will come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As above, how can action only involving leading civilised countries, be considered &amp;quot;united action&amp;quot;? Who&#39;s defining &amp;quot;civilised&amp;quot; here? No mention in this book of Africa for example. Don&#39;t they get a say? Again, better among equals...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the proletariat during its contest with the bourgeoisie is compelled, by the force of circumstances, to organise itself as a class, if, by means of a revolution, it makes itself the ruling class, and, as such, sweeps away by force the old conditions of production, then it will, along with these conditions, have swept away the conditions for the existence of class antagonisms and of classes generally, and will thereby have abolished its own supremacy as a class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the utopia of communism. It is also wishful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tour de table of different types of communism that have or would fail, followed by the assumption that Marx&#39;s &amp;quot;communism&amp;quot; will not. Feudal Socialism, Petty Bourgoise Socialism, German or True Socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the latter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preserve this class is to preserve the existing state of things in Germany. The industrial and political supremacy of the bourgeoisie threatens it with certain destruction — on the one hand, from the concentration of capital; on the other, from the rise of a revolutionary proletariat. “True” Socialism appeared to kill these two birds with one stone. It spread like an epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Conservative or Bourgoise Socialism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A part of the bourgeoisie is desirous of redressing social grievances in order to secure the continued existence of bourgeois society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this section belong economists, philanthropists, humanitarians, improvers of the condition of the working class, organisers of charity, members of societies for the prevention of cruelty to animals, temperance fanatics, hole-and-corner reformers of every imaginable kind. This form of socialism has, moreover, been worked out into complete systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this description - very good! Fully agree, this is some sort of half way house to keep the rich in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They wish for a bourgeoisie without a proletariat. The bourgeoisie naturally conceives the world in which it is supreme to be the best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second, and more practical, but less systematic, form of this Socialism sought to depreciate every revolutionary movement in the eyes of the working class by showing that no mere political reform, but only a change in the material conditions of existence, in economical relations, could be of any advantage to them.....but administrative reforms, based on the continued existence of these relations; reforms, therefore, that in no respect affect the relations between capital and labour, but, at the best, lessen the cost, and simplify the administrative work, of bourgeois government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bourgeois Socialism attains adequate expression when, and only when, it becomes a mere figure of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free trade: for the benefit of the working class. Protective duties: for the benefit of the working class. Prison Reform: for the benefit of the working class. This is the last word and the only seriously meant word of bourgeois socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is summed up in the phrase: the bourgeois is a bourgeois — for the benefit of the working class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we seem to be in this form of socialism. The question is: where will it end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter considers that Germany, at the time, was closest to some half way house to Communism and therefore had quite a small proletariat. They were still fighting the aristocracy. Interesting that less than 100 years later the Nazis were in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in the appenices to the docmument, Engels, in &amp;quot;Principles of Communism&amp;quot;, considers the revolution will be easiest in England, hardest in Germany, based on the relvative sizes of the proletariat in those countries - larger in England, smaller in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the manifesto is very open about the probable need for forced / armed revolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all these movements, they bring to the front, as the leading question in each, the property question, no matter what its degree of development at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Communists disdain to conceal their views and aims. They openly declare that their ends can be attained only by the forcible overthrow of all existing social conditions. Let the ruling classes tremble at a Communistic revolution. The proletarians have nothing to lose but their chains. They have a world to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you have to fight for what you believe is right. Forcing others against their will to believe it will never work. There will always be those who don&#39;t believe. Suppressing them doesn&#39;t work for long.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The work archives</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/work-archives/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-16T19:12:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/work-archives/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I did some physical archiving, as opposed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/archiving/&quot;&gt;virtual archiving&lt;/a&gt; I do here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues of mine had spent the last few weeks disappearing into our archives, to clear them out ahead of our move to a new building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it turns out most of them can be binned, so I spent Wednesday afternoon helping them finish off the process of sorting them into paper for recycling, CDs, plastic for the main rubbish and piles and piles of folders presumably for shipping into the past for reuse in a time when they were useful. All our archives have now been digital for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was really a case of chucking stuff out rather than archiving, but it felt good and I felt productive once I saw the boxes we filled! 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also interesting to see colleagues&#39; names on the project folders from 15 years ago. I now feel slightly less frustrated when I have to ask them for the third time how to do things. I&#39;ve only been in the unit 4 years!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Inaccessible Code</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inaccessible-code/"/>
		<updated>2023-08-16T12:18:27Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/inaccessible-code/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like this summary from Eric of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ericwbailey.website/published/the-five-types-of-people-who-produce-inaccessible-code/&quot;&gt;types of people who create inaccessible code&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code, but do not realize they are doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code and realize they are doing so, but do not know how to fix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code, and do not care about fixing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code that they think is accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who create inaccessible code that our industry thinks is accessible, but experientially is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Surface Detail</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/surface-detail/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-27T20:00:33Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/surface-detail/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;by Iain M Banks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got through this book in 10 days whilst on holiday. Reading it over such a short time frame helped me to keep the storyline fresh in mind. Maybe because of this, I feel it is certainly one of the better Culture series books. Somewhat unusually it ties up all the loose ends and leaves nothing unexplained. Maybe because by now readers are aware of the all encompassing power of the Culture civilisation and the trickery this enables them engage in. And yet it is not necessarily the most powerful civilisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/surface-detail.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Fotinovo</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fotinovo/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-25T21:30:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/fotinovo/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/&quot;&gt;short hike yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, we decided to follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hikes-and-walks.com/hike/bulgaria/fotinski-waterfalls&quot;&gt;Waterfall trail in Fotinovo&lt;/a&gt;, about 100 minutes drive from Plovdiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 6km hike to the waterfalls and back, as well as a steep descent to actually see the waterfalls. Most of the info I could find about the trail indicated this was an easy hike. The descent to the waterfalls and subsequent climb back up are anything but. It didn&#39;t help that we did the hike on the hottest day of the year so far. It was 33°C in Fotinovo and 40°C in Plovdiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The waterfalls were interesting and worth the effort, but not exceptionally so. Maybe they are more imposing in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The waterfalls seen from the bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The bridge at the bottom to get to the waterfalls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Another view of the waterfalls from the bottom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The river flowing into the waterfalls, which the trail follows to get to the falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-5.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The edge of the village where the trail starts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-6.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A workshop where we got some directions at the start of the trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/fotinovo-7.webp&quot; alt=&quot;The trail leading past some meadows towards the waterfalls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Byala Cherkva</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-24T21:30:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/byala-cherkva/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We spent an hour hiking around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/3Dz1p9kAH55Z9jAr9&quot;&gt;Byala Cherkva&lt;/a&gt; area inn order to escape the 39°C heat in Plovdiv. It&#39;s not really a starting point for any trails, so we just set off down the road and turned round 45 minutes later. It was a nice walk, still hot despite being half way up the Rodopi mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/byala-cherkva-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Brown butterfly with orange trim containing black dots nestling on a yellow flower with the green foliage blurred in the background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Kapana</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/kapana/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-23T17:47:29Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/kapana/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://visitkapana.bg/en/about-the-district/&quot;&gt;Kapana&lt;/a&gt; (Капана), Bulgarian for trap, is an area of central Plovdiv with small streets.  Traditional where handicrafts people setup their workshops, it was then a bit of an artists area. For as long as I have known Plovdiv (around 20 years) it was always a bit of a rundown and underused area, from a tourist perspective. It has been completely redone in the last couple of years and turned into a great street cafe area. It&#39;s especially busy in the evenings and judging by the languages I heard, popular with the tourists. Well worth a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Kapana in the late evening&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Kapana in the late evening&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a great vegan meal in a small cafe called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veggic.bg/&quot;&gt;VEGGIC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/kapana-3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;VEGGIC restaurant serving great vegan food&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course all progress has its downsides. This sort of gentrification also means the people who used to run art ateliers and crafts workshops here can no longer afford to do so. Thankfully though there are, in my opinion, still enough areas of central Plovdiv that need restoring that those traders will find somewhere nearby to set up shop. I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Oft Robin</title>
		<link href="https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/oft-robin/"/>
		<updated>2023-07-16T23:32:05Z</updated>
		<id>https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/oft-robin/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another lovely evening &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robin.is/posts/2023/beebop-plovdiv/&quot;&gt;watching jazz again&lt;/a&gt;, this time listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://viktorbenev.com/oft-robin.html&quot;&gt;Oft Robin&lt;/a&gt; in &amp;quot;Room 1&amp;quot; of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bnr.bg/plovdiv/&quot;&gt;Radio Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt; building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 18 people watching, possibly we were the only ones not included in &amp;quot;Family and Friends&amp;quot; 🙂. The group is great so it&#39;s surprising there weren&#39;t more people in the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/oft-robin-1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.robin.is/assets/images/2023/oft-robin-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
